<?xml version="1.0"?>
<list>
 <event>
  <id>
   1
  </id>
  <name>
   Community Health &amp; Epidemiology Seminar Series - Adrian MacKenzie - "The Importance of Division of Work and Clinical Focus in Health Human Resource Planning: Dynamic, Multi-professional, Needs-based Simulation Model "
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-07 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-07 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/07/community_health___epidemiology_seminar_series___adrian_mackenzie____the_importance_of_division_of_work_and_clinical_focus_in_health_human_resource_planning__dynamic__multi_professional__needs_based_simulation_model__.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   CH&amp;E Classroom, r. 409, Centre for Clinical Research, 5790 University Avenue, Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Abstract: Comprehensive health human resources (HHR) planning is essential for addressing population health needs and meeting other common health care system objectives. For reasons that remain unclear, conceptually invalid approaches to HHR planning remain commonplace in Canada and other countries. The overarching aim of this study is to assess the feasibility of using a dynamic, multi-professional, needs-based simulation model to inform HHR planning in Nova Scotia. Objective of this model is to estimate the supply of and requirements for physicians, nurses, social workers, and psychologists to address anxiety and depression among school-aged children in Nova Scotia through 2032; and to identify technical and political factors affecting the choice of HHR planning models in Nova Scotia. With regards to methods, a dynamic, multi-professional, needs-based simulation model was used to achieve the first objective. A series of key informant interviews with HHR planners from different Nova Scotia stakeholder groups was conducted to address the second objective. 
 Simulation modeling suggests Nova Scotia currently lacks the number and mix of HHR required to address anxiety and depression among its school-aged children, and that this problem will worsen without intervention. Examples of policy interventions with the potential to address simulated HHR gaps are provided. The most important factor identified as affecting the choice of HHR planning model in Nova Scotia was the buy-in of key stakeholder groups. Other factors identified as particularly important in determining this choice were the model's balance between comprehensiveness and complexity, the political and technical capacity of individuals and organizations responsible for HHR planning, and concerns regarding the availability of appropriate planning data to populate the model. 
 Conclusion: Use of this model to inform HHR planning in Nova Scotia is feasible with appropriate engagement of key stakeholders. The structure and presentation of the model are viewed by HHR planners in the province as being suited to facilitating such engagement. Coordinated investments are needed to ensure adequate planning capacity among the individuals and organizations responsible for HHR planning in Nova Scotia, and the availability of adequate data to inform HHR and health system planning.
Biography: Adrian MacKenzie is a PhD Candidate in the Division of Community Health and Humanities in the Faculty of Medicine at the Memorial University of Newfoundland. He is a Doctoral Trainee and Associated Researcher with the WHO/PAHO Collaborating Centre at Dalhousie University, where he also holds an Adjunct appointment with the Department of Community Health &amp; Epidemiology. ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   2
  </id>
  <name>
   Community Health &amp; Epidemiology Seminar Series – Special Seminar - Bradley Johnston, PhD &amp; Regina El Dib, PhD - "Trustworthy and novel dietary guidelines: Early results of systematic reviews on red and processed meat"
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-08 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-08 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/08/community_health___epidemiology_seminar_series___special_seminar___bradley_johnston__phd___regina_el_dib__phd____trustworthy_and_novel_dietary_guidelines__early_results_of_systematic_reviews_on_red_and_processed_meat__.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   CH&amp;E Classroom, r. 409, Centre for Clinical Research, 5790 University Avenue, Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Abstract 
Background: Many nutritional guidelines do not adhere to internationally recognized standards for trustworthy guidelines. For instance, existing guidelines include limited high quality systematic reviews of both observational studies and randomized trials, and within these systematic reviews, guideline developers have not conducted independent analyses on food intake using dose-response and dietary pattern meta-analysis. 
 Objective: To explore meta-analysis results of various study designs, setting an example for other organizations involved in nutrition-related guideline development.
Methods: We will provide an overview of our systematic review methods, including risk of bias assessment for randomized trials and observational studies, dose-response meta-analysis, methods for assessing the overall certainty of evidence, and a novel method developed to further explore the potential causal association between red and processed meat intake and adverse health outcomes (e.g. cancer, cardiometabolic disease) – meta-analysis of dietary pattern studies. We will also present our systematic review methods on assessing consumers' values and preferences that will be used to inform food-based recommendations, and how values and preferences are used in making guideline recommendations. 
Conclusion: It is anticipated that NutriRECS methods will serve as a model for other nutrition-related organizations wishing to develop high quality systematic reviews, reviews that will inform trustworthy and novel guideline recommendations.
Biographies 
Dr. Bradley Johnston (PhD) is an Associate Professor with the Department of Community Health &amp; Epidemiology at Dalhousie University were he leads research and teaching on the methodology and conduct of clinical and public health practice guidelines, patient-reported outcome measures, as well as randomized controlled trials. His work involves the application of these methods to a wide range of areas, with a particular interest in the education, principles and practice of evidence-based nutrition.  The trust of his research work is as the Director and Co-founder of NutriRECS, an international consortium aiming to develop trustworthy and novel nutritional guideline recommendations on major nutrition, food and dietary pattern questions. 
Dr. Regina El Dib (PhD) is a visiting professor and clinical epidemiologist with the Department of Community Health &amp; Epidemiology at Dalhousie University. She is a tenured Assistant Professor in the Institute of Science and Technology, Estadual Paulista University (Unesp), Brazil, and is the Director of the systematic review unit of the Botucatu Medical School, Unesp, registered in the Brazilian National Council for Scientific and Technological Development. She has published more than 100 peer-reviewed articles, primarily involving systematic reviews and meta-analysis of interventional, prognostic and diagnostic accuracy studies, as well as research on methods for advancing evidence synthesis methodology. She is also an adjunct researcher with the McMaster Institute of Urology, McMaster University in Canada, collaborating on a number of primary and secondary studies in kidney cancer.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   3
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-09 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-09 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   4
  </id>
  <name>
   Boosting Your Positive Outlook (Halifax and Truro)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-10 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-10 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/10/boosting_your_positive_outlook__halifax_and_truro_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   https://events-tm.dal.ca/workshop.php?id=2645
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Consistently focusing on the negative side of an issue can greatly contribute to stress.  When thinking this way, physical changes take place in the body's chemistry increasing stress levels and affecting performance and well-being.  This session equips participants with tools for understanding the ways in which this seemingly automatic negative thinking occurs, recognizing its typical manifestations and developing a process for tackling these thoughs effectively.
Learning Objectives:

Define the "Stress Whirlpool"
Understanding how negative thoughts work and their impact on your body
Develop a strategy for combating negative thoughts and increasing your positive outlook

Feel free to bring your lunch.
This seminar is offered in collaboration with Morneau Shepell through your Employee &amp; Family Assistance Program (EFAP). This program offers immediate and confidential help for you and your family, helping you achieve better health and well-being. Call your EFAP toll-free, 24 hours a day, seven days a week: 1-800-387-4765, or visit their online services at:workhealthlife.com.
Please register​ for this event through the  Employee Learning
 Calendar. Please indicate whether you will attend in Halifax or Truro when you register.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   5
  </id>
  <name>
   Feminist Seminar Series | Dr. Sherry Pictou "Indigenous Women: Struggle, Resilience and Resurgence"
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-11 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-11 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/11/feminist_seminar_series___dr__sherry_pictou__indigenous_women__struggle__resilience_and_resurgence_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   McCain Building, 6135 University Avenue, Room 2190
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   6
  </id>
  <name>
   28th Annual Student Musicale
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-13 15:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-13 15:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/13/28th_annual_student_musicale.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie Arts Centre, Room 406
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   The Dalhousie Women’s Division, in collaboration with the Fountain School of Performing Arts, is pleased to present the 28th Student Musicale. This annual concert highlights the diverse talents of student musicians at Dalhousie. Please join us on Sunday, January 13, 2019 at 3:00 p.m. in the Dalhousie Arts Centre. A reception will follow the performance in room 401, allowing an opportunity for the audience to mingle, and meet and chat with the performers.
All proceeds from this event support the Women’s Division’s scholarship and bursary fund for students.
 Tickets are $10 for students and $15 for adults, and will be available at the door. ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Tickets are $10 for students and $15 for adults, and will be available at the door. ​
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   7
  </id>
  <name>
   Lecture with Maestro Judith Yan: Less is more - Beethoven's 5th
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-14 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-14 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/14/lecture_with_maestro_judith_yan__less_is_more___beethoven_s_5th.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 406, Dalhousie Arts Centre, 6101 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Canadian conductor Judith Yan is equally adept at conducting opera, ballet, and symphony, and her career takes her to the world's major stages and concert halls.
 judithyan.com
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   8
  </id>
  <name>
   Architecture lecture by Letitia Meynell (Halifax)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-15 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-15 10:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/15/architecture_lecture_by_letitia_meynell__halifax_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Cineplex Theatre 7, Park Lane Mall, 5657 Spring Garden Road
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Letitia Meynell is an Associate Professor of Philosophy at Dalhousie University, cross-appointed with Gender and Women’s Studies. She specializes in philosophy of science, epistemology, aesthetics, and feminist philosophy.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   9
  </id>
  <name>
   Architecture lecture by Manon Asselin (Montreal)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-16 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-16 10:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/16/architecture_lecture_by_manon_asselin__montreal_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Cineplex Theatre 7, Park Lane Mall, 5657 Spring Garden Road
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Manon Asselin is Principal at Atelier TAG and Professor at University of Montreal School of Architecture. She seeks to create meaningful spaces by reinterpreting the civic function of architecture through the careful study of the sociocultural contexts within which a given program operates.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   10
  </id>
  <name>
   Innovation Rounds: ESCF as an Enabler of Ideas to Products to Exit: Experiences from Panag Pharma
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-17 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-17 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/17/innovation_rounds__escf_as_an_enabler_of_ideas_to_products_to_exit__experiences_from_panag_pharma.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bethune Ballroom, 1st Fl. Bethune Building (VG Site) QEII 1276 South Park St.
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Panag Pharma is focused on development of a new generation of pain management therapeutics based on exploiting the endocannabinoid system.  Join us to learn about Panag and how Innovacorp's ESCF grants have supported their evolution.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   11
  </id>
  <name>
   Architecture panel discussion by Jennifer Corson and Roger Lewis (Halifax)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-18 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-18 10:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/18/architecture_panel_discussion_by_jennifer_corson_and_roger_lewis__halifax_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Cineplex Theatre 7, Park Lane Mall, 5657 Spring Garden Road
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Jennifer Corson is an architect, business owner, and author of The Resourceful Renovator. She is Senior Partner at Solterre Design, which focuses on energy-efficient renovations, historic restorations, and innovative off-grid residential and commercial construction.
Roger Lewis is Curator of Ethnology at the Nova Scotia Museum, with research interests in Mi’kmaw knowledge-practices tied to land and resource use. He works closely with Mi’kmaw communities throughout Nova Scotia to gather and record information about their cultural objects.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   12
  </id>
  <name>
   Audition Preparation Day
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-19 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-19 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/19/audition_preparation_day.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Tips on how to do a successful audition.   And entire day of informative clinics and workshops.   Preview of technical and theoretial requirements.   In-depth instruction by Fountain School of Performing Arts profs. 
Family, friends and private / group instructors are welcome.    To register please contact Jessica - jmailhio@dal.ca.   Deadline to reserve a spot is January 11.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   13
  </id>
  <name>
   Community Health &amp; Epidemiology Seminar Series - Dr. Mohammad Hajizadeh - "Inequalities in Psychological Distress and Suicidal Behaviour Between Indigenous and Non-Indigenous Population in Canada: What Explains the Differences?"
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-21 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-21 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/21/community_health___epidemiology_seminar_series___dr__mohammad_hajizadeh____inequalities_in_psychological_distress_and_suicidal_behaviour_between_indigenous_and_non_indigenous_population_in_canada__what_explains_the_differences__.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   CH&amp;E Classroom, r. 409, Centre for Clinical Research, 5790 University Avenue, Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Abstract: Inequalities in the psychological distress and suicide rates between Indigenous and non-Indigenous population continue to exist in Canada. Using data from the 2012 Canadian Community Health Survey – Mental Health (n= 25,113) we investigated demographic, socioeconomic, sociocultural and geographic factors underlying the variation in the prevalence of moderate-to-serious psychological distress (10-item Kessler Psychological Distress Scale [K10] scores &gt; 24) and lifetime suicidal ideation and lifetime suicide plan between Indigenous populations living off-reserve and non-Indigenous population in Canada. An extension of the Blinder–Oaxaca (BO) technique to non-linear models was used to decompose the differences in the prevalence into two parts: the proportion attributable to the different levels of the covariates between Indigenous and non-Indigenous populations (the endowment effect or explained part) and a proportion attributable to those covariates having different effects on psychological distress and suicidal behaviours in Indigenous and non-Indigenous populations (the response effect or unexplained part). The prevalence of moderate-to-serious psychological distress, lifetime suicidal ideation and lifetime suicide plan among the non-Indigenous population in Canada were found to be 5.8, 9.5, 2.4%, respectively. The corresponding figures for Indigenous peoples were 10, 18.6 and 7.8%, respectively. We found that the variation in psychological distress is mostly explained by the differences in the sociodemographic, socioeconomic and sociocultural factors between Indigenous and non-Indigenous populations in Canada. The results indicated that if covariates (e.g., income and employment status) were made to be identical in Indigenous and non-Indigenous populations, the difference in the psychological distress between these populations would have been reduced by 77%.  The differences in the prevalence of lifetime suicidal ideation and lifetime suicide plan, however, were mainly explained by the response effect. Improving covariates among Indigenous peoples through plans like income equalisation or education subsidies may reduce the gap in psychological distress between Indigenous and non-Indigenous populations in Canada. Since the response effect chiefly explains variations in suicidal behaviours, further research is required to understand these differences in Canada.
Biography: Dr. Mohammad Hajizadeh is an Assistant Professor at the School of Health Administration at Dalhousie University and cross-appointed with the School of Health and Human Performance and Department of Community Health and Epidemiology. He is also an Associate Research Scholar at the Healthy Populations Institute (HPI). Dr. Hajizadeh received his PhD in Economics from the University of Queensland and have held postdoctoral positions at McGill and Western universities. A health economist by training, his primary research interests are analyzing equity of health care, measuring inequality in health and evaluating health and social policies.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   14
  </id>
  <name>
   Budget Discussion Forum
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-22 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-22 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/22/budget_discussion_forum.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Jacob Slonim Room (430), 4th floor, Goldberg Computer Science Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Faculty, staff and students are invited to attend one of two discussion forums on priorities for the 2019-20 operating budget. The forums will include a short presentation on the university’s operating budget, followed by a workshop-style discussion on pressures and priorities. Your input will help shape recommendations for next year’s budget.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   15
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-23 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-23 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing2.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   16
  </id>
  <name>
   Atlantic Conference on Public Administration
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-24 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-25 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/24/atlantic_conference_on_public_administration.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Four Points by Sheraton Halifax 1496 Hollis St, Halifax, NS B3J 3Z1
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   Over the past fifty years, the Atlantic Canadian region has experienced large changes in its population, demographics, economics, and health systems. Currently, the region is growing more culturally diverse while youth outmigration is on the rise and an increasing percentage of the population are aging adults. These changes are impacting healthcare spending, community health planning as well as economic strategies. At ACPA 2019, we will discuss the future health of Atlantic Canada in an interactive, innovative format. Discussions will be focused on economic health, community health, and healthcare to share perspectives, promising practices, and explore innovative ideas and solutions for a Healthier Atlantic Canada.
  </description>
  <cost>
   $200
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   17
  </id>
  <name>
   Feminist Seminar Series | Dr. Benita Bunjun, Interrogating Colonial Encounters: The Un/Making of White Feminist Entitlement
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-25 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-25 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/25/feminist_seminar_series___dr__benita_bunjun__interrogating_colonial_encounters__the_un_making_of_white_feminist_entitlement.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   McCain Building, 6135 University Ave Room 2190
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Using an intersectional critical race feminist analysis, Dr. Bunjun will be examining the complexities, negotiations, and disruptions of power relations through time within one feminist organization, Vancouver Status of Women (VSW), and the specific trajectory of multiple and intersecting histories and locations of this particular feminist organization born out of hegemonic white Liberal Second Wave feminism in British Columbia, Canada.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   18
  </id>
  <name>
   Senate meeting
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-28 15:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-28 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/28/senate_meeting.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Theatre A, Tupper Medical Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Meetings
  </category>
  <description>
   Senate meets on the second and fourth Mondays of the month, from September through June. Learn more about Senate and its business at the Senate website.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   19
  </id>
  <name>
   Law &amp; Technology Society Eminent Speaker Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-29 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-29 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/29/law___technology_society_eminent_speaker_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 104, Weldon Law Building, 6061 University Ave., Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   McCarthy Tétrault's national innovation leader, Matt Peters, will discuss innovation in the legal profession and the skills needed to position students as effective and valuable future lawyers. Peters is the strategy lead for MT&amp;gtPlay, a division of the firm at the heart of the intersection of gaming, technology, and law. ​This series is presented by the Schulich School of Law's Law &amp; Technology Institute and ​the student-run ​Law &amp; Technology Society.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   20
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-30 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-30 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing3.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   21
  </id>
  <name>
   Assessing the Trudeau Foreign Policy Record
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-01-31 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-01-31 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/31/assessing_the_trudeau_foreign_policy_record.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Council Chambers (Room 270), Student Union Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Dr. Kim Richard Nossal, Queen’s University
The Liberals under Justin Trudeau will face the voters in October 2019. This presentation looks at the Trudeau government’s overall foreign policy record, arguing that much of the change in Canadian foreign policy promised by Trudeau in 2015 has foundered on the major shifts in global politics that occurred shortly after the Liberals took office.
Free and open to the public
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   22
  </id>
  <name>
   Opera "L’ÉTOILE"
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-01 07:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-01 07:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/31/opera__l__toile_.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Sir James Dunn Theatre, Dal Arts Centre, 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Chabrier's opéra bouffe, L’Étoile, performed in English by Fountain School voice students, straddles the line beteen serious art music and light operetta. With its sophisticated harmonies and vocal writing, and a witty new English adaptation by Jeremy Sams, L’Étoile is rooted in the French comic tradition. It's a fantastical, absurd, and sometimes even surreal story of oppression, love, and intrigue.
Tickets available , Dalhousie Arts Centre Box Office, 902-494-3820
  </description>
  <cost>
   $15
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   23
  </id>
  <name>
   SURGE VR/AR Deep Dive 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-02 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-02 18:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/01/surge_vr_ar_deep_dive_2019.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox (Life Science Centre Room 2660 in Oceanography)
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   SURGE is an innovation sandbox at Dalhousie University funded by the Nova Scotia government, whose aim is to train science students to translate scientific discovery into economic growth and solutions to the world’s big problems.
About The Event
This Deep Dive event is a 3 day event all about exploring augmented and virtual reality technologies and its applications to different project areas. It will begin with exploration and demonstrations from companies that are currently using augmented and virtual reality as a tool in their own work. We hope this will inspire you for ideas of your own to pitch on how to apply AR/VR for solutions to real world problems. Teams of 4-5 will work over the weekend to develop a science-focused AR/VR application. You may form a team before the event, or show up and pitch yourself on Friday afternoon and find a team. Over the course of the rest of the weekend, teams will develop their ideas into prototypes. Teams will present their results on Sunday afternoon to a panel of judges with prizes for the best projects. Open to the greater community not just Dalhousie Students, NO CODING EXPERIENCE REQUIRED!
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   24
  </id>
  <name>
   SURGE VR/AR Deep Dive 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-03 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-03 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/01/surge_vr_ar_deep_dive_2019.event.html/showing2.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox (Life Science Centre Room 2660 in Oceanography)
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   SURGE is an innovation sandbox at Dalhousie University funded by the Nova Scotia government, whose aim is to train science students to translate scientific discovery into economic growth and solutions to the world’s big problems.
About The Event
This Deep Dive event is a 3 day event all about exploring augmented and virtual reality technologies and its applications to different project areas. It will begin with exploration and demonstrations from companies that are currently using augmented and virtual reality as a tool in their own work. We hope this will inspire you for ideas of your own to pitch on how to apply AR/VR for solutions to real world problems. Teams of 4-5 will work over the weekend to develop a science-focused AR/VR application. You may form a team before the event, or show up and pitch yourself on Friday afternoon and find a team. Over the course of the rest of the weekend, teams will develop their ideas into prototypes. Teams will present their results on Sunday afternoon to a panel of judges with prizes for the best projects. Open to the greater community not just Dalhousie Students, NO CODING EXPERIENCE REQUIRED!
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   25
  </id>
  <name>
   Dalhousie Cardiac Research Day 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-04 08:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-04 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/04/dalhousie_cardiac_research_day_2019.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Royal Bank Theatre &amp; Lobby area, QEII HSC Halifax Infirmary
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   The Division of Cardiac Surgery, Division of Cardiology and The Cardiovascular Research Group collaboratively organize this annual event to promote research among trainees.  Abstract competition open to all trainees, residents, medical students, and fellows.  The Keynote Speaker this year is Dr. Carrie Bourassa is Scientific Director of the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, Institute of Indigenous Peoples Health (IIPH), Deparmtne to f Communicty Health &amp; Epidemiology, College of Medicine / University of Saskatchewan.  Please join us at the Royal Bank Theatre on Feb 4th for the Keynote Address 08:00-09:00; Podium and Poster Sessions from 12:00-17:00.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   26
  </id>
  <name>
   MLIS Open House
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-05 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-05 14:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/05/mlis_open_house.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rowe Building Room 3089
  </location>
  <category>
   Admissions
  </category>
  <description>
   Learn how our MLIS degree can broaden your career options by joining us for our next Open House on February 5th! Please share. RSVP's requried: https://www.dal.ca/faculty/management/school-of-information-management/news-events/open-house.html​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   27
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-06 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-06 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing4.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   28
  </id>
  <name>
   IWK Research Rounds
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-07 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-07 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/02/iwk_research_rounds.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Cineplex-OE Smith Theatre, IWK Health Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Maternal Health Outcomes of Incarcerated Women
Speaker: Martha Paynter, MSc, MDE, RN
This presentation describes the evidence of health outcomes among this population, the legislation and policies governing health services and the challenges to maternal wellbeing.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   29
  </id>
  <name>
   2019 Glyn Berry Lecture
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-08 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-08 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/08/2019_glyn_berry_lecture.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rowe Management Building, Room 1009
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Dr. Paul Evans (Professor, UBC) will give the annual Glyn Berry lecture entitled "Living with China in an era of great power rivalry: Canadian opinion”. Where he will explore what should a post-engagement China strategy look like?
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   30
  </id>
  <name>
   33rd Annual Cameron Conference
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-09 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-09 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/09/33rd_annual_cameron_conference.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   2nd and 3rd Floor Link, LSC
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   Approximately 39 students in the Biology and Marine Biology Honours programs will present their thesis research, in areas ranging from molecular genetics to the behaviour of large vertebrates. Many of the past presenters at the Cameron Conference have gone on to distinguished careers in biological research and teaching, the health professions, public service, and business. The Cameron Conference is our best forum for highlighting the work of our young scholars, at this early stage of their scientific careers.
The morning and afternoon sessions of the conference include both poster presentations and selected oral presentations. Coffee and other refreshments and lunch are provided.
The Cameron Conference is named in honour of the late M. L. Cameron, a professor at Dalhousie for many years who devoted much of his academic career to the development of our Honours program, and to the education, training, and mentoring of Biology students.
We are proud to host this event, which show-cases the research done by our Honours students.  We look forward to seeing you there.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   31
  </id>
  <name>
   Black and Gold Dance Team Showcase - Revolution
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-10 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-10 19:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/10/black_and_gold_dance_team_showcase___revolution.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie's competitive dance team Black and Gold presents their annual showcase REVOLUTION!
 Join us on February 10th at 7pm in the McInnes Room (student union building) for a night filled with dance! 
 Come enjoy a variety of pieces from our team, along with the performances of three other local studios in Halifax!
 Featuring Performances from:
 Elle Dance academy
 Maritime Dance Academy
 Element Dance Studio ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   McInnes Room - Dalhousie Student Union Building
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   32
  </id>
  <name>
   Number Theory Seminar
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-11 14:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-11 15:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/11/number_theory_seminar.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chase Building, Room 319
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Presented by: Keith Johnson
Title: “Rational Polynomials which Preserve the Ring of 2x2 Matrices with Integer Coefficients”
Abstract: 
​​​​If $M_2(\mathbb{Z})$ denotes the ring of $2\times 2$ matrices with coefficients in $\mathbb{Z}$ then there are polynomials in $p(x)\in\mathbb{Q}[x]$ for which $p(M)\in M_2(\mathbb{Z})$ if $M\in M_2(\mathbb{Z})$ without $p(x)$ having all integer coefficients itself. $(x^6+x^5+x^3+x^2)/2$ is an example. Describing all polynomials in $\mathbb{Q}[x]$ with this property is an open problem and this talk will describe how much is known so far.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   33
  </id>
  <name>
   Information Without Borders Conference
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-12 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-12 16:15:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/12/information_without_borders_conference.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   McInnes Room, 2nd Floor, Dalhousie Student Union Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   On February 12th, 2019, the 13th annual student-run Information Without Borders Conference (IWB) will be held in the McInnes Room at Dalhousie University’s Student Union Building. The topic for the 2019 conference is: Information Accessibility. The conference will explore issues and concerns around who has access to information, how it is obtained, and how knowledge transfer could be facilitated. Registration is now open! Visit iwbconference.ca
 or contact iwb@dal.ca for more information!​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   34
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-13 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-13 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing5.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   35
  </id>
  <name>
   Innovation Rounds - Sleep Apnea Therapy: How NovaResp Tech. is making patients safer and more comfortable
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-14 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-14 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/14/innovation_rounds___sleep_apnea_therapy__how_novaresp_tech__is_making_patients_safer_and_more_comfortable.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bethune Building Ballroom, 1st Fl. Bethune (VG Site) 1276 South Park St.
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Hamed Hanafi, PhD, NovaResp Technologies will explain how new technology being developed here in Halifax can help patients with sleep apnea.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   36
  </id>
  <name>
   Ada: A Self-driving Laboratory for Accelerating Materials Discovery
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-15 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-15 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/15/ada__a_self_driving_laboratory_for_accelerating_materials_discovery.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chemistry Room 226
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Professor Curtis P. Berlinguette
Departments of Chemistry and
Chemical &amp; Biological Engineering
The University of British Columbia
https://www.chem.ubc.ca/curtis-berlinguette
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   37
  </id>
  <name>
   What is Universal Design? Unravelling the myth from the reality
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-19 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-19 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/21/what_is_universal_design__unravelling_the_myth_from_the_reality.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   B400, Killam Library
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Presenter: Kirsten Jones, B.Sc. &amp; M.Sc. 
Register for this Workshop: https://events-tm.dal.ca/workshop.php?id=2757                                                                                 
Often, Universal Design in classrooms is considered too hard, too difficult, or too challenging to implement in academic settings. In reality, this is far from the truth universal design is an extension of our teaching styles, not an opposition to them. This workshop is intended as an introduction to universal design principles. It will help to provide context on what universal design is, what it means to students, and how to incorporate it into existing course design. 
Kirsten Jones is a two time Alumni from Dalhousie University with a B.Sc and an M.Sc in Chemistry. Her interest in helping faculty and staff with incorporating Universal Design principles began in her Masters degree and stems from her own experiences as a student with a learning disability. Her outreach within this area includes consulting with faculty and staff about their course designs, co-authoring a book on Equity and Diversity, and presenting to Faculty at conferences about these principles in relation to her experiences as an individual with learning disabilities. ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   38
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-20 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-20 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing6.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   39
  </id>
  <name>
   The Memorialist: Keynote Address
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-21 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-21 19:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/21/the_memorialist__keynote_address.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   MacAloney Room (406), Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   FREE ADMISSION -- Limited Seating

 The Memorialist: Keynote Address is a performance that accompanies the exhibition The Memorialist by D’Arcy Wilson. Departing from the lecture hall as a traditional site of knowledge exchange and academic research, Wilson employs the podium to deliver a lecture about the first public zoo in North America: Andrew Downs' Zoological Gardens. Yet, facts break down into storytelling, oscillating between truth and whimsy, while addressing Andrew Downs’ early ideals of wildlife conservation. The hour-long PowerPoint is comprised of imagery and new media created and collected by Wilson, that laments the colonial mistreatment of nature, presenting narratives of conflicting care and harm that fueled the artist’s research.

 The performance will be followed by a reception in the Gallery, with a community welcome to Laura Ritchie, Director/Curator of MSVU Art Gallery. (8:00-9:30 PM)

 Refreshments will be provided, as well as a cash bar. Free Admission.

 Join the Facebook event here: https://www.facebook.com/events/1209144095908205/


D'Arcy Wilson: The Memorialist

 18 January to 14 April

 Andrew Downs’ Zoological Gardens opened in Halifax, Nova Scotia, at the edge of town in 1847. Stretching over one hundred acres in the area adjacent to what is now known as the Armdale Roundabout, for more than 20 years the Gardens housed regional and exotic animals in sprawling wooded enclosures. The proprietor, known to care deeply for the animals in his keep, was also a master taxidermist, supplying specimens to the world’s leading scientific institutions of the time. Downs’ Gardens was the first public zoo dedicated to the study of nature in North America, and yet, these gardens also signalled the broken bridge between colonial settlers and the natural world, becoming a “living museum” of wildlife in a patch of forest just off the Halifax Peninsula.

 The Memorialist—a term with which Downs self-identified in his practice—departs from this story, following the undercurrents of colonialism that permeate Western Culture’s understanding of nature, while retracing the complex geography of care and harm that characterized nineteenth century efforts to collect and preserve natural specimens (and occasionally their habitat) under the context of an expanding dominion. In this installation of her ongoing research driven project, D’Arcy Wilson presents a combination of still photography, video projections, a 14-ft diorama, a selection of museum and archival objects, and performances that tease out the contradictions at play behind the preservationist impulse and the museological framing of the natural world.
ACCESSIBILITY: Dalhousie Art Gallery is wheelchair accessible by elevator through the main entrance, 6101 University Avenue. Although there is no parking on University Avenue, there is 3 hour, metered accessibility parking around the corner on Seymour Street. The second floor (above the gallery) has a gender-neutral, wheelchair accessible washroom with a change table.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   40
  </id>
  <name>
   Molecules under Torture: Lasers, Forces, Voltages, and Beyond
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-22 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-22 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/22/molecules_under_torture__lasers__forces__voltages__and_beyond.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chemistry Room 226
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Professor Ignacio Franco
Departments of Chemistry and Physics
University of Rochester
https://www.chem.rochester.edu/groups/franco/?page_id=486
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   41
  </id>
  <name>
   Number Theory Seminar
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-25 14:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-25 15:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/25/number_theory_seminar.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chase Room 319
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Presented by: Lin Jiu
Title: “Random Walk Approaches to Identities on Higher-order Bernoulli and Euler Polynomials”
Abstract: We use random walks as an approach to obtain identities for higher-order Bernoulli and Euler polynomials. In particular, we study the cases of a 1-dimensional linear reflected Brownian motion and of a 3-dimensional Bessel process. By decomposing the successive hitting times of two, three, and four fixed levels of these random walks, we obtain non-trivial identi-ties that involve higher-order Bernoulli and Euler polynomials.
This is joint work with Christophe Vignat.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   42
  </id>
  <name>
   Gefilte Fish and Roast Duck with Orange Slices: A Treasure for My Daughter and the Creation of a Jewish Cultural Orthodoxy in Postwar Montreal
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-26 13:05:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-26 14:05:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/02/26/gefilte_fish_and_roast_duck_with_orange_slices__a_treasure_for_my_daughter_and_the_creation_of_a_jewish_cultural_orthodoxy_in_postwar_montreal.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   25 Banting Hall (Dalhousie Agricultural Campus, Bible Hill)
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The community is invited to History 3000's food history seminars. February 26th's seminar is focused on Andrea Eidinger's chapter in Edible Histories, Cultural Politics: Towards a Canadian Food History (U of Toronto Press, 2012), edited by Franca Iacovetta, Valerie J. Korinek, and Marlene Epp. Refreshments are typically served. For more information, contact Professor Stiles at Deborah.Stiles@dal.ca or 902-893-6705.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   43
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-27 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-27 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing7.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   44
  </id>
  <name>
   Dalhousie Program &amp; Major Expo (for students)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-02-28 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-02-28 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/28/dalhousie_program___major_expo__for_students_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie Student Union Building (SUB), McInnes Room (second floor), 6136 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie and King's students are invited to connect with faculty, advisors and students from across Dalhousie to explore programs, majors, minors, co-ops and more! ​
To request materials to promote the event to your students, please email tanis.trainor@dal.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   45
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Faculty of Computer Science
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-01 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-01 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/01/phd_defence___faculty_of_computer_science.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Hossein Mohammadhassanzadeh​​​​​, PhD candidate fro​m the Faculty of Computer Science​, will be defending their ​​thesis entitled "Plausible Reasoning over Knowledge Graphs: A Novel Approach for Semantics-Based Health Data Analytics" on Friday, March 1st at 10​:00 a​​m.​​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   46
  </id>
  <name>
   iGEM and SURGE Hackathon
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-02 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-02 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/01/igem_and_surge_hackathon.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox (Life Science Centre Room 2660)
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Are you a Biologist? Ethicist? Computer Scientist? Anywhere in Between? Dalhousie iGEM is looking for a diverse range of undergraduate students to join our team and help us build on previous years of success at the international Giant Jamboree!
Join Dalhousie iGEM and SURGE at our "iGEM Hackathon" Weekend, where you (and some friends) can exercise your synthetic biology muscles, create a project of your very own, and pitch it to our panel of Judges. AWARDS for top three teams!
What is the iGEM competition?
iGEM is an international competition in the subject of synthetic biology. Held each fall in Boston, MA, over 6,000 university students from all over the world come together to pitch their project ideas and designs using synthetic biology to solve a real world issue.
For more information about the iGEM program visit the following: http://igem.org
What is SURGE?
SURGE is an innovation sandbox funded by the Nova Scotia government, whose aim is to train science students to translate scientific discovery into economic growth and solutions to the world’s big problems. Learn more about SURGE at surgeinnovation.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   47
  </id>
  <name>
   iGEM and SURGE Hackathon
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-03 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-03 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/01/igem_and_surge_hackathon.event.html/showing2.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox (Life Science Centre Room 2660)
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Are you a Biologist? Ethicist? Computer Scientist? Anywhere in Between? Dalhousie iGEM is looking for a diverse range of undergraduate students to join our team and help us build on previous years of success at the international Giant Jamboree!
Join Dalhousie iGEM and SURGE at our "iGEM Hackathon" Weekend, where you (and some friends) can exercise your synthetic biology muscles, create a project of your very own, and pitch it to our panel of Judges. AWARDS for top three teams!
What is the iGEM competition?
iGEM is an international competition in the subject of synthetic biology. Held each fall in Boston, MA, over 6,000 university students from all over the world come together to pitch their project ideas and designs using synthetic biology to solve a real world issue.
For more information about the iGEM program visit the following: http://igem.org
What is SURGE?
SURGE is an innovation sandbox funded by the Nova Scotia government, whose aim is to train science students to translate scientific discovery into economic growth and solutions to the world’s big problems. Learn more about SURGE at surgeinnovation.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   48
  </id>
  <name>
   Ask an Astronaut
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-04 10:45:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-04 10:45:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/04/ask_an_astronaut.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium
  </location>
  <category>
  </category>
  <description>
   In partnership with the Canadian Space Agency, Dalhousie University will host an interactive live-link with the International Space Station, where astronaut David Saint-Jacques will answer audiences questions live from space.
  </description>
  <cost>
   This event is free, but registration is required. Registration will open at noon on Friday, February 22.
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   49
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Mechanical Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-05 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-05 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/05/phd_defence___department_of_mechanical_engineering.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Gregory Sweet​​​​​, PhD candidate fro​m the Department of Mechanical Engineering​​, will be defending their ​​thesis entitled "Improving the Mechanical and Physical Properties of an Aluminum Powder Metallurgy Metal Matrix Composite via Hot Upset Forging" on Tuesday, March 5th at 9​​:00 a​​m.​​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   50
  </id>
  <name>
   Public Policy Forum Digital Democracy 101 Lecture: Understanding Synthetic Media
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-06 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-06 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/06/public_policy_forum_digital_democracy_101_lecture__understanding_synthetic_media.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   University Hall, MacDonald Building, 6300 Coburg Rd.
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   In this free public lecture, Carl Miller, Research Director at Demos, will explain how synthetic media can harm democracy. The lecture will be followed by a discussion and question and answer period moderated by Howard Ramos ​and Karen Foster from Dalhousie's Sociology and Social Anthropology Department. 
New technology can create fake photos and videos that look very real. Movies and TV use this technology to create amazing special effects, but when it gets in the wrong hands it can be used to show real people doing and saying things that they haven't. It's called a deepfake, and it can be especially dangerous during an election, a time when we make important choices based on what candidates say and do.
This is one of three free public lectures hosted the Public Policy Forum and its partners that explain how our democracy is affected by the manipulation of information and trust on digital platforms.
All are welcome to attend. This is a free event, but registration is required. Register now.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   51
  </id>
  <name>
   Innovation Rounds: Integrating Exercise into Health Care: Innovative Strategies to Engage Practitioners and Patients
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-07 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-07 08:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/07/innovation_rounds__integrating_exercise_into_health_care__innovative_strategies_to_engage_practitioners_and_patients.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bethune Ballroom, 1st Fl. Bethune Building, VG Hospital Site
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Dr. Jonathon Fowles will discuss strategies to integrate physical activity counselling into clinical practice, and identify opportunities to build collaborative processes in health care and communities to support patients in getting exercise as medicine.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   52
  </id>
  <name>
   JMEUCE Public Lecture - The Economic Impact of Immigrants: What do Europeans really think?
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-08 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-08 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/08/jmeuce_public_lecture___the_economic_impact_of_immigrants__what_do_europeans_really_think_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1009, Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The JMEUCE is pleased to announce a public lecture on
THE ECONOMIC IMPACT OF IMMIGRANTS: WHAT DO EUROPEANS REALLY THINK?
with guest speaker DR ZEYNEP OZKOK, Associate Professor, Department of Economics, St Francis Xavier University
​This public lecture is based on a paper, co-authored by Zeynep Ozkok and two colleagues at the St FX Department of Economics looking at "Evolving Attitudes on
 the Economic Impact of Immigrants: Evidence from the European Social Survey".
​All welcome.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   53
  </id>
  <name>
   March Madness Clearance &amp; BOGO Sale
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-11 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-16 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/11/march_madness_clearance___bogo_sale.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dal Bookstore - SUB and AC locations
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Save up to 50% on a wide selection of Dal branded merchandise today through Friday (AC location) and Saturday (SUB location).
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   54
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Microbiology and Immunology
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-12 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-12 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/12/phd_defence___department_of_microbiology_and_immunology.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Eric Pringle, PhD candidate fro​m the Department of Microbiology and Immunology​​, will be defending their ​​thesis entitled "​Translational Efficiency Of Herpesvirus Messenger Ribonucleic Acids" on Tuesday, March 12th at 9:30 am.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   55
  </id>
  <name>
   Free coffee at Bicentennial Common Pop-up event
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-13 10:15:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-13 10:15:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/13/free_coffee_at_bicentennial_common_pop_up_event.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Killam Library Entrance
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Embrace winter with a free hot beverage and the latest information about Bicentennial Common​!​
Bicentennial Common is an ambitious reimaging of the high-traffic area stretching from LeMarchant Street  up past the Killam Library to the beginning of the upper portion of Studley Quad​. This new public space will honour the legacy of the university’s bicentennial in the years ahead.

As the design continues, Dal is trying out various  elements, including furniture and four new patio heaters. The heaters will be officially turned on at the event, but they will remain in place from now on.  Take a look at the latest design and let us know what you would like to see in the space.  
Learn more in this Dalnews article. https://www.dal.ca/news/2018/03/12/bicentennial-commons-aims-to-redesign-the-heart-of-studley-campu.html
#DalCommon
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   56
  </id>
  <name>
   David Schroeder Music &amp; Culture Lecture Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-14 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-14 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/14/david_schroeder_music___culture_lecture_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 406, Dalhousie Arts Centre, 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   WILLIAM CHENG

But the Nazis Loved Music, Too 
William Change is Associate Professor of Music at Dartmouth College and the author of two award-winning books, Sound Play: Video Games and the Musical Imagination (2014) and Just Vibrations: The Purpose of Sounding Good (2016). He teaches and writes about topics in media, ethics, disability, race, play, performance, and sonic weaponry, and he has written for outlets such as Washington Post, Slate, Huffington Post, Pacific Standard, and TIME Magazine.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   57
  </id>
  <name>
   Active Learning Workshop: Teaching Sustainability in an Interdisciplinary Environment
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-15 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-15 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/15/active_learning_workshop__teaching_sustainability_in_an_interdisciplinary_environment.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   B400, Killam Library
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Presenters: Georgia Klein and Andrew Bergel
 Friday, March 15, 2019
 11:00 AM – Noon
The Environment, Sustainability, and Society double major at Dalhousie University began ten years ago as a new program for incoming undergraduates. This interdisciplinary program was designed to address "Wicked Problems" that help students become change-makers and leaders with a deeper understanding of complex connections between the Environment, Social Justice, and an innovative Economy. 
This workshop will begin with a discussion on the curriculum development in the College of Sustainability. Obstacles and opportunities in the curriculum development led to an Experiential/Active Learning approach throughout the core curriculum. This includes various tools, such as: Problem based learning, Interdisciplinary Co-teaching models, Active Simulations. How these activities connect the core classes and their learning outcomes, along with how they complement each other throughout our interdisciplinary program structure will be presented to the attendees. 
Our presentation will be followed by a workshop where we invite attendees to join groups in a short exercise/brainstorm session to identify barriers and opportunities to implement some of these tools in your classes/curriculum. We will then gather again as a group for a final discussion to share future possibilities for implementation.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   58
  </id>
  <name>
   Afrofuturism: a panel discussion
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-18 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-18 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/18/afrofuturism__a_panel_discussion.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rowe Building, Room 3089, 6100 University Ave.
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Join us for this panel discussion on Afrofuturism with Dr. Asha Jeffers of King's and Dr. Isaac Saney of Dalhousie. Kewoba Carter of Dal's International Centre will moderate. 

 This is event is presented by the Dalhousie Libraries in support of this year's Dal Reads book, Brown Girl in the Ring by Nalo Hopkinson. Set in the near future in a dystopic Toronto, Brown Girl in the Ring contains themes of folklore, feminism, and magic realism steeped in Afro-Caribbean culture.

 About the panelists and moderator:

Dr. Asha Jeffers:
 Dr. Jeffers is a Faculty Fellow at University of King’s College. She has a PhD in English literature from York University. Her research focused on literature about the children of immigrants — the second generation — across national and ethnic lines. She’s particularly interested in myths of the past and myths of the future.

Dr. Isaac Saney:
 Dr. Saney is Director of Dalhousie’s Transition Year Program, established to redress educational barriers and injustices facing the Mi’kmaq Nation, other First Nations, and African Nova Scotians. His teaching and scholarship encompasses Africa, the Caribbean, the US Civil Rights Movement, Cuba, and Black Nova Scotian history. He is a community activist and participant in the anti-war movement and the anti-racist struggle, with roots in the Black Nova Scotian community and the Caribbean.

Kewoba Carter:
 Kewoba is an International Student Advisor &amp; Co-ordinator in Dalhousie’s International Centre. Originally from the island of Dominica, she taught secondary school English Caribbean Literature for two years. She then moved to Canada and graduated from Dalhousie with a Bachelor of Arts Combined Honours in International Development Studies and English.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   59
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Chemistry
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-19 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-19 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/19/phd_defence___department_of_chemistry.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Fabien Lindeperg, PhD candidate fro​m the Department of Chemistry​​, will be defending their ​​thesis entitled "Investigation of P-H, O-H, and Si-H Oxidative Addition Involving Group 9 Metal Psip Complexes​" on Tuesday, March 19th at 9:30 am.​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   60
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-20 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-20 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing10.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   61
  </id>
  <name>
   MASc Defence - Kaitlin Miles
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-21 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-21 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/21/masc_defence___kaitlin_miles.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   MA 310, 5269 Morris St.
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   This thesis utilizes discrete event simulation to model four outpatient physiotherapy locations in the Central Zone of the Nova Scotia Health Authority. Centralization of intake is being considered to increase efficiency and allow for pooling of resources.
The model allows the user to modify the scheduling policy, effectively changing the queuing discipline, to schedule patients in to New and Return appointments.
Management is considering sending low priority patients to other locations than their origin hospital to alleviate their long and volatile wait times. The model also allows the user to modify the master schedule of available appointments, e.g. change the number of appointments or adjust the mix of New and Return appointments. ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   62
  </id>
  <name>
   University of King’s College Spring Open House
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-22 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-22 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/22/university_of_king_s_college_spring_open_house.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   University of King's College
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Join us from 10 a.m. to 2 p.m. on March 22 for our Spring Open House. Meet with an admissions expert, learn about King’s undergraduate programs and student supports, hear from current students, tour the campus, and discover what life at King’s could be like. We’re offering free on-the-spot admissions to anyone who wants to apply to King’s the day of the event, and we’ll have great door prizes! Doors open at 9:30 a.m.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   63
  </id>
  <name>
   Woodwinds Masterclass with Kinan Azmeh
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-23 10:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-23 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/23/woodwinds_masterclass_with_kinan_azmeh.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 121, Dalhousie Arts Centre, 6101 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Kinan Azmeh's distinctive sound across different musical genres has gained him international recognition as a clarinetist and composer. He has toured the world and performed with leading orchestras in Europe, Western Asia, South America, and the USA.
SNS Performance:  March 24, 2:00 pm
kinanazmeh.com
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   64
  </id>
  <name>
   SUPERHEROES, Dalhousie Chorus
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-24 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-24 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/24/superheroes__dalhousie_chorus.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Paul O'Regan Hall, Halifax Central Library, 5440 Spring Garden Road
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   The serious, the sublime, and the silly will all make an appearance in this program as the Dal Chorus tells tales of superheroes (and heroines!) caught in jeopardy or saving the day. Drawing on stories from literature and paying tribute to real-life superheroes who have overcome incredible obstacles, this program will have something for everyone! Conducted by Christina Murray.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   65
  </id>
  <name>
   Beyond the Binary: Grappling with sex and gender in biomedical research
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-25 10:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-25 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/25/beyond_the_binary__grappling_with_sex_and_gender_in_biomedical_research.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Tupper Theatre A
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Featuring Dr. Stacey Ritz with opening remarks from Jasmine Walsh, AVP Dalhousie Human Resources.
Stacey Ritz is an Associate Professor in the Department of Pathology &amp; Molecular Medicine, and Assistant Dean of the Bachelor of Health Sciences (Honours) Program at McMaster. She received her PhD from the Molecular Immunology, Virology &amp; Inflammation Program at McMaster University. As a PI, her laboratory investigated the influence of particulate air pollution on allergy and autoimmune disease; more recently, her work has shifted to focus on how sex/gender considerations can be integrated into laboratory-based research, and critical pedagogy in health sciences education.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   66
  </id>
  <name>
   Psychology and Neuroscience Colloquium
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-26 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-26 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/26/psychology_and_neuroscience_colloquium.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   LSC P4258
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Testing a Trauma Model to Understand Involvement in Bullying
Speaker: Dr. Wendy Craig, Queens University
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   67
  </id>
  <name>
   Vanier Institute of the Family Conference 2019: Families in Canada
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-27 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-28 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/27/vanier_institute_of_the_family_conference_2019__families_in_canada.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Student Union Building, Room 307
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie University will be hosting a satellite event for the Families in Canada Conference 2019.
The conference will feature local interactive presentations in the mornings, with live-streamed keynotes and panels from the main conference site in Ottawa each afternoon. Halifax is one of five satellite sites for the conference. Dalhousie is partnering with the IWK Health Centre, MSVU, and Wisdom2Action Ltd to host the event. 
This conference will be very interdisciplinary and will include researchers, government officials and community service providers. Dalhousie researchers, academics and students from across a number of faculties will feature prominently. Confirmed speakers from Dal include:
-Dr. Noni MacDonald, Professor of Paediatrics &amp; Infectious Diseases
-Dr. Penny Corkum, Department of Psychology and Neuroscience , Department of Psychiatry
- Nicole MacKenzie, PhD candidate, Clinical Psychology
-Fateha Bappee, PhD candidate, Faculty of Computer Science
 -Dr. Alice Aiken, Vice-President, Research and Innovation
-Dr. Howard Ramos, Associate Dean of Research, FASS
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   68
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department Of Microbiology And Immunology
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-28 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-28 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/28/phd_defence___department_of_microbiology_and_immunology.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Benjamin Johnston, PhD candidate from the Department Of Microbiology And Immunology, will be defending their thesis entitled "Kaposi’s Sarcoma-Associated Herpesvirus Modulates the Unfolded Protein Response During Lytic Replication" on Thursday, March 28, 2019 at 9:30 a.m.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   69
  </id>
  <name>
   NMR Across the Periodic Table: Observing "Invisible" Nuclides in Solid Materials
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-29 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-29 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/29/nmr_across_the_periodic_table__observing__invisible__nuclides_in_solid_materials.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chemistry Room 226
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Professor Robert W. Schurko
Departments of Chemistry and Biochemistry
University of Windsor
http://www.uwindsor.ca/science/chemistry/476/faculty-robert-w-schurko
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   70
  </id>
  <name>
   2019 Black Excellence in STEM Conference
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-03-30 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-03-30 16:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/03/30/2019_black_excellence_in_stem_conference.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   The Discovery Centre, 1215 Lower Water Street, Halifax, NS
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   The 2019 Black Excellence in STEM: A One-day Scholars Event for Faculty, Students, and Industry Professionals conference will highlight STEM research, engage high school learners in STEM activities and discussions, and explore health-related issues in the African Canadian communities.
https://www.dal.ca/faculty/science/imhotep/media_center/2019BEIS.html
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   71
  </id>
  <name>
   Number Theory Seminar
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-01 02:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-01 15:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/01/number_theory_seminar.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chase Room 319
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Presented by: Mason Maxwell
​Title: “Irreducibility of Generalized Stern Polynomials”
​Abstract: ​
​​We study the irreducibility of two types of generalized Stern polynomials introduced by Karl Dilcher and Larry Ericksen in 2017. The classical Stern integer sequence, remarkable in its own right, was extended in 2007 by  Klavžar, Milutinović, and Petr to the Stern polynomials $B_n(z)$ defined by $B_0(z)=0$, $B_1(z)=1$, and for $n\geq1$ by $B_{2n}(z)=zB_n(z)$, $B_{2n+1}(z)=B_n(z)+B_{n+1}(z)$. Ulas conjectured that $B_p(z)$ is irreducible whenever $p$ is prime; this has been verified for the first $10^6$ primes and various cases were proved by Schinzel and by Dilcher, Kidwai, and Tomkins. In this talk we study the analogous problem for the generalized Stern polynomials. In the process, we survey the theory of cyclotomic polynomials and several important theorems about irreducibility of certain classes of polynomials. We end with a conjecture about reducible generalized Stern polynomials having cyclotomic factors.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   72
  </id>
  <name>
   Psychology and Neuroscience Colloquium
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-02 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-02 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/02/psychology_and_neuroscience_colloquium.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   LSC P4258
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Looking through the eyes of another: What do we know about eye 
 movements and can we use other people's perceptual input to alter 
 performance​
Speaker: Mike Dodd, University of Nebraska-Lincoln
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   73
  </id>
  <name>
   BRIC NS Student Seminar Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-03 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-03 13:15:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/03/bric_ns_student_seminar_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 315, Collaborative Health Education Building, 5793 University Ave., Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The BRIC NS Student Seminar Series is an opportunity for students to present their completed or in-progress research.  Presenters cover a wide range of topics and disciplines, with the common thread of primary and integrated health care research running throughout.  Everyone is welcome!
For remote attendance options please email bricns@dal.ca.
Logan Lawrence will present "Developing a tool for assessing policy capacity: A case study of nurse practitioners in primary care in Nova Scotia."
Rachel Olliver will present "Exploring Postpartum Sexual Health in Nova Scotia Using Feminist Poststructuralism."
About the speakers
Logan Lawrence is a PhD candidate in Dalhousie's PhD Health program. His doctoral research involves testing and adapting a framework for studying policy capacity in Nova Scotia's health system. He has received financial support for his studies from the Killam Trust, Nova Scotia Health Research Foundation, Nova Scotia Health Authority, Maritime SPOR Support Unit, and Nova Scotia Graduate Scholarship. He also currently holds a Health Systems Impact Fellowship from the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, which enables him to work with the Nova Scotia Department of Health and Wellness and learn the craft of health policy-making. Logan's enjoyment of understanding different facets of ideas extends outside of academia: reading and writing, cooking and eating, playing and listening to music, being active and making quiet. He holds a Master of Science in Kinesiology from Dalhousie, and originally hails from Alberta.
Rachel Olliver is a first-year PhD in Nursing student at Dalhousie University. She completed her BScN degree in 2016 at UBC Okanagan and has clinical experience in acute medicine and surgery, with a current position as a Registered Nurse on the Adult Surgical Unit (Women's Health) at the IWK Health Centre. Rachel's areas of research interest include global health, women's health, and maternal health. She has previously completed nursing and research placements in Zambia and Tanzania.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   74
  </id>
  <name>
   IWK Research Rounds
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-04 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-04 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/04/iwk_research_rounds.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   OE Smith/Cinaplex Theatre IWK Health Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Social Interaction and Youth Mental Health
Speaker: Dr. Sandra Meier. Associate Professor of Psychiatry, Dalhousie University and Tier 2 Canada Research Chair in Developmental Psychopathology and youth Mental Health
Anxiety and depression are among the most common mental disorders worldwide. Patients with these disorders are severely limited in social interactions, and are frequently isolated and have fewer friends. It is often unclear which exact behavioral features make patients unsuccessful in social interactions.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   75
  </id>
  <name>
   Faculty of Engineering 2019 Capstone Conference
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-05 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-05 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/05/faculty_of_engineering_2019_capstone_conference_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Westin Hotel, Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   The Dalhousie Engineering Capstone Conference (DECC) is the largest event for senior year engineering students, incorporating all engineering disciplines within the Faculty. The conference gives students the opportunity to showcase how their Capstone Projects integrate course work and engineering design skills to provide innovative solutions to local industry partners​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   76
  </id>
  <name>
   Signature Event: The Grand Parade
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-06 19:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-06 19:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/05/signature_event__the_grand_parade.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Kenneth C. Rowe Hall, Pier 21, 1055 Marginal Road
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   18th century opulence in costume! Fourth year students of the Fountain  School's Costume Studies program join with the Dal Wind Ensemble for our annual historical costume show. Join us for an evening of unique exploration in an unexpected setting. This event will showcase the creative pairing of rhythmic and colourful music with lush historical dress, design, and choreography by Fountain School students. We are proud to present this exciting collaboration with the help of the Traves Performance Excellence Fund.
  </description>
  <cost>
   $15
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   77
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Psychology and Neuroscience
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-08 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-08 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/08/phd_defence___department_of_psychology_and_neuroscience.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Tamara Speth, PhD candidate from the Department of Psychology and Neuroscience​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Impact of Cumulative Sleep Restriction on Sleep Physiology in Children with and without Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD)​" on Monday, April 8th, at 2:00 p.m.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   78
  </id>
  <name>
   Saving Strategies: Easy concept, difficult reality (Halifax, Truro and Saint John)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-09 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-09 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/09/saving_strategies__easy_concept__difficult_reality__halifax__truro_and_saint_john_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   https://events-tm.dal.ca/workshop.php?id=2831
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   This workshop is offered by Organization Health and Wellness for staff and faculty. Please register here.​
Learn how to save more, pay down debt, spend less and invest in the future from a volunteer from Charterered Professional Accountants Canada.
Learning objectives for participants:

how to save more to pay down debt
saving and a reduction in spending often go together to achieve success
use the power of compounding to make savings grow
start to invest in the future to realize goals and dreams and prepare for a comfortable retirement
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   79
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-10 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-10 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing12.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   80
  </id>
  <name>
   Innovation Rounds: One Patient One Record: Next steps to ensure we are ready
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-11 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-11 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/11/innovation_rounds__one_patient_one_record__next_steps_to_ensure_we_are_ready.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bethune Ballrooom, 1st Fl. Bethune Building, VG Hospital Site
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Presenters: ​Keltie Jaimeson, Senior Director OPOR for NSHA and Alyson Lamb, Interim Clinical Transformation and Informatics Officer and IWK Lead.
The presentation will provide an overview of the OPOR strategy for NS, its scope and the potential implications for research.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   81
  </id>
  <name>
   Strides toward inclusive design in the first year chemistry lab through closed captioned video (inside and outside the lab)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-12 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-12 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/12/strides_toward_inclusive_design_in_the_first_year_chemistry_lab_through_closed_captioned_video__inside_and_outside_the_lab_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   B400, Killam Library
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   Presenters: Mark Wall and Jennifer MacDonald
Lunch &amp; Learn: April 12th, 2019
 Noon - 1 PM
 B400, Killam Library

Bring your lunch and enjoy this noon-hour information session with Mark Wall and Jennifer MacDonald
With a major course re-design underway in the first year chemistry program, the first year teaching team aims to reach all students through inclusive design. The laboratory relies on instructional video inside and outside the lab to prepare prior to lab sessions and support students in their post-lab data analysis. Following a migration of all laboratory videos to YouTube in Summer 2017, Drs. Wall and MacDonald planned to have all videos closed captioned before the launch of the new program; however, this process was expedited in Winter 2019 when a hard-of-hearing student self-identified in our lab. 
In this session, the presenters will discuss their personal experience with migrating video content to YouTube for better course integration (between CAPA, LMS, and lab manual) and the pathway in which they captioned lab videos (with the help of undergraduate/graduate student TAs) for a just-in-time delivery inside and outside the lab.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   82
  </id>
  <name>
   Tupper Band 40th Anniversary Concert
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-13 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-13 19:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/13/tupper_band_40th_anniversary_concert.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Halifax Central Library-Paull O'Regan Hall
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   No charge for students. The proceeds go towards the Music-in-Medicine Scholarship Fund​.
The concert features music from a wide variety of sources, ranging from musical theatre and movies to songs of ABBA and Freddie Mercury, even including a Spanish march and a waltz.
In 1979 a group of Dalhousie medical students, faculty members and healthcare professionals embarked on a venture that no Canadian medical school had previously attempted – they decided to form a concert band. From those earliest days, the Band been directed by Dr. Bernard Badley, a former vice-dean of the Faculty of Medicine and C.E.O. of the Victoria General Hospital.
  </description>
  <cost>
   $10
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   83
  </id>
  <name>
   Palm Sunday in the King's College Chapel
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-14 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-14 12:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/14/palm_sunday_in_the_king_s_college_chapel.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   King's College Chapel, 6350 Coburg Rd
  </location>
  <category>
   Religious &amp; Spiritual
  </category>
  <description>
   A Sung Service of Holy Communion and outdoor Palm Procession with Donkey in the King's Quad. Includes the blessing of the animals (for Tabitha the Donkey). Followed by coffee hour and treats. All welcome.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   84
  </id>
  <name>
   Ombudsperson Office Review - Open Session for Students
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-15 15:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-15 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/15/ombudsperson_office_review___open_session_for_students.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   3207 Mona Campbell Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie University is undertaking a review of the Office of the Ombudsperson that was established for students in 2016. The review will consider and make recommendations on the mandate and functioning of the office and how to improve its effectiveness. Following the review, a search for the next Ombudsperson will be undertaken.

As part of the review process, an external reviewer will be meeting with key stakeholders. Students are invited to meet with the external reviewer, Mr. Stephen Strople, former Secretary General of McGill University. Light refreshments will be provided.

The Scope of the Review, the Terms of Reference of the Office of Ombudsperson and the Annual Report for 2016-17 may be accessed at: https://www.dal.ca/campus_life/safety-respect/student-rights-and-responsibilities/where-to-get-help/ombudsperson.html
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   85
  </id>
  <name>
   Sanofi Biogenius Canada Regional Competition
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-16 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-16 19:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/16/sanofi_biogenius_canada_regional_competition.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Sir Charles Tupper Building Foyer
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   The @biogeniusCA competition fosters young high school minds and talent by challenging participants to carry out groundbreaking biotechnology research. Support the next great minds in science at the Atlantic @biogeniusCA event, April 16 in the Tupper lobby https://bit.ly/2WIfTNa ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   86
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-17 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-17 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/01/09/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing13.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   87
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Psychology and Neuroscience
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-18 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-18 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/18/phd_defence___department_of_psychology_and_neuroscience.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Stephanie Snow, PhD candidate from the Department of Psychology and Neuroscience, will be defending their thesis entitled "​Finding Balance: Identifying Ways to Improve the Delivery of Surgical Care to Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder" on Monday, April 8th at 9:00 am.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   88
  </id>
  <name>
   Good Friday in the King's College Chapel
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-19 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-19 11:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/19/good_friday_in_the_king_s_college_chapel.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   King's College Chapel, 6350 Coburg Rd
  </location>
  <category>
   Religious &amp; Spiritual
  </category>
  <description>
   Words from the King's Chaplain, Fr Ranall Ingalls: 
"The ancient 'Synaxis' for this day includes the veneration of the Cross, drawing the whole body into prayer, calling us out of our heads really to be present to suffering and to love."
Address by poet-professor Dr Alyda Faber.
This is a non-eucharistic choral service sung by the Chapel Choir including the famous setting of Psalm 51 Miserere Mei by Gregorio Allegri, as well as music by T.L. de Victoria and Clemens (non Papa). 
​Followed by Good Friday Hot Cross Buns in the Senior Common Room. All students, staff, faculty, and friends of Kings/Dal are welcome!!
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   89
  </id>
  <name>
   The Great Vigil of Easter and First Mass of Easter
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-20 23:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-20 02:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/20/the_great_vigil_of_easter_and_first_mass_of_easter.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   King's College Chapel, 6350 Coburg Rd
  </location>
  <category>
   Religious &amp; Spiritual
  </category>
  <description>
   The liturgy begins with the lighting of fire in darkness and the proclamation, 'The Light of Christ'! That light is welcomed by an ancient hymn, the 'Exultet,' calling the whole Cosmos to rejoice in the light. The Vigil moves into the First Mass of Easter, followed by the Resurrection Feast - a full banquet begun in the wee hours of the morning and celebrated until Dawn. 
Address by poet-professor Dr. Alyda Faber. The Chapel Choir sings music by J. Langlais, G.P. da Palestrina, P. Halley, and J. Taverner, with organ postlude by J. Alain. 
​Service begins at 11:00 PM, but come early to get a seat.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   90
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Mathematics and Statistics
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-22 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-22 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/22/phd_defence___department_of_mathematics_and_statistics.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 430, The Goldberg Computer Science Building, 6050 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Michael Lambert, PhD candidate from the Department of Mathematics and Statistics, will be defending their thesis entitled "An Elementary Account of Flat 2-Functors" on Monday, April 22nd, at 9:00 am.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   91
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Physics and Atmospheric Science
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-23 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-23 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/23/phd_defence___department_of_physics_and_atmospheric_science.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Melanie Hammer, PhD candidate from the Department of Physics and Atmospheric Science, will be defending their thesis entitled "Inferring Atmospheric Aerosol Properties from Satellite Observations and a​​ Global Chemical Transport Model" on Tuesday, April 23rd, at 10:00 am.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   92
  </id>
  <name>
   2019 Atlantic Conference for Administrative Professionals
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-24 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-24 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/24/2019_atlantic_conference_for_administrative_professionals_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Westin Nova Scotian Hotel, 1181 Hollis Street, Halifax, NS
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   An annual professional development conference serving administrative professionals in the Atlantic region​.
Agenda may be found at https://sparkconferences.com/admin-halifax/agenda/
  </description>
  <cost>
   $699.00
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   93
  </id>
  <name>
   Official opening of the Emera ideaHUB
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-25 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-25 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/25/official_opening_of_the_emera_ideahub.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Emera ideaHUB, 3rd floor of the Emera IDEA Building, Sexton Campus, 5283 Morris Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie will celebrate the official launch of the Emera ideaHUB on April 25th.
 The Emera ideaHUB is an advanced incubator and maker-space that empowers the next generation of innovators, entrepreneurs, and start-ups. It is strengthening Atlantic Canada’s innovation culture by building networks between universities, companies, governments, entrepreneurs and investors.
Event details
 10:00 a.m. Formal remarks.
 10:30 a.m. Tours of the Emera ideaHUB and product demonstrations. Light refreshments will be served.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   94
  </id>
  <name>
   DalSpace: A place to preserve the intellectual output of the Dalhousie community Webinar (Scholarship @ Dal Libraries Series)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-26 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-26 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/26/dalspace__a_place_to_preserve_the_intellectual_output_of_the_dalhousie_community_webinar__scholarship___dal_libraries_series_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online only, participants will receive webinar link when they register.
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   Are you interested in providing a global audience of current and future scholars with access to your research and scholarship? This session will talk about how you can use Dalhousie's Institutional Repository (DalSpace) to support barrier-free access to your articles, policy documents, supplementary data, image collections and much more.
Learning Objectives:

Learn about the role of Institutional Repositories and why they are preferable to other options
Discover how DalSpace supports Open Access
Find out what  kinds of materials are encouraged in DalSpace and how to deposit​

Geoff Brown is the Digital Scholarship and Government Information Librarian at Dalhousie Libraries. He manages DalSpace, oversees the libraries' journal hosting service and is working to support open textbook development both at Dalhousie University and in the Atlantic region.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   95
  </id>
  <name>
   SURGE Launch Oceans Event
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-27 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-27 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/26/surge_launch_oceans_event.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox - LSC Oceanography 2660
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Are you interested in Ocean Science, Ocean Tech, Aquaculture, Fishing, Ocean Data and/or other areas of Ocean Research? Do you have a great idea for a solution that could solve one of the ocean's many problems? Come out to the Launch Oceans Event April 26-28and learn how to build an oceans startup in Atlantic Canada – one of the fastest-growing oceans business ecosystems in the world.
Come develop and “test drive” a business idea. We will teach you proven methods of defining problems, creating solutions, evaluating product-market fit, and systematically building an evidence-based business model.
Come as a team, or alone and form a team at the event. All are welcome, from any education level and discipline. Prizes will be awarded for the best business models.
Teams may also continue in the 8 week Launch Oceans Summer Incubator.​
Register at surge-launch-oceans19.eventbrite.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   96
  </id>
  <name>
   SURGE Launch Oceans Event
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-28 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-28 17:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/26/surge_launch_oceans_event.event.html/showing2.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox - LSC Oceanography 2660
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Are you interested in Ocean Science, Ocean Tech, Aquaculture, Fishing, Ocean Data and/or other areas of Ocean Research? Do you have a great idea for a solution that could solve one of the ocean's many problems? Come out to the Launch Oceans Event April 26-28and learn how to build an oceans startup in Atlantic Canada – one of the fastest-growing oceans business ecosystems in the world.
Come develop and “test drive” a business idea. We will teach you proven methods of defining problems, creating solutions, evaluating product-market fit, and systematically building an evidence-based business model.
Come as a team, or alone and form a team at the event. All are welcome, from any education level and discipline. Prizes will be awarded for the best business models.
Teams may also continue in the 8 week Launch Oceans Summer Incubator.​
Register at surge-launch-oceans19.eventbrite.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   97
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Oceanography
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-29 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-29 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/29/phd_defence___department_of_oceanography.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Steven Bruce Martin, PhD candidate from the Department of Oceanography​, will be defending their thesis entitled "One Minute at a Time: Advancing our Ability to Estimate Effects of Human Sound on Marine Life." on Monday, April 29th, at 2:00 pm.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   98
  </id>
  <name>
   Communications for Complex Situations Workshop for Faculty &amp; Staff - April 30
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-04-30 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-04-30 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/30/communications_for_complex_situations_workshop_for_faculty___staff___april_30.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Group Room 1, 2nd floor, LeMarchant Place, 1246 LeMarchant Street (just down the hall from Student Health and Wellness)
  </location>
  <category>
   Health and Wellness
  </category>
  <description>
   ​"Communications for Complex Conversations" is a workshop for front-line staff and faculty that would like to increase their confidence in helping students who are experiencing a variety of emotions, such as anger and crying, or a high-conflict communication style.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   99
  </id>
  <name>
   Dalhousie Conference on Teaching and Learning (DCUTL) 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-01 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-02 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/01/dalhousie_conference_on_teaching_and_learning__dcutl__2019.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, Dalhousie University
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   ​"Diving Deep: Engaging Students Through Active Learning"
Dalhousie Conference on University Teaching and Learning
May 1st &amp; 2nd, 2019
Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building
Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS
Register Online at the DCUTL Conference Website
Keynote Speaker: Dr. Sara Harris
"Finding Our Ways to Active Learning"
May 1, 2019
Dr. Sara Harris is Professor of Teaching in the department of Earth, Ocean, and Atmospheric Sciences, Associate Dean Academic for the Faculty of Science at the University of British Columbia (UBC), and a 3M National Teaching Fellow. 
More Info​
Keynote Speaker: Dr. Teri Balser
"Active learning takes active teaching – reducing resistance by managing risk?"
May 2, 2019
Dr. Teri Balser is Provost and Vice President Academic at Dalhousie University, and a Principal Fellow of the U.K.-based Higher Education Academy. In addition to recognition as an accomplished international research scholar, Dr. Balser has received numerous accolades for ther teaching accomplishments.
More Info
Pre-Conference Science Teaching Workshop
April 30, 2019, 9:00 AM - 4:00 PM
"Making Space for Questioning"
Join us for a full-day workshop where we practice, share, and develop strategies for active learning through questioning in our science classrooms. While giving you the opportunity to work with examples from your own and others’ university science teaching, we’ll explore how asking and answering questions can help our students build their confidence and independence, as well as develop a deeper understanding of science. 
More Info
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   100
  </id>
  <name>
   IWK Research Rounds
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-02 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-02 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/02/iwk_research_rounds.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Cineplex OE Smith Theatre; IWK Health Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Women's Health Research: Evidence Impacting Care and Outcomes
Speaker: Erna Snelgrove-Clarke
Dr. Snelgrove-Clarke's program of research focuses on the identification of successful strategies for using evidence in maternal newborn practice. She is exploring the transfer of knowledge through mixed methodlogy, concentrating on the relationships of health care professionals, organizations and decision-makers.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   101
  </id>
  <name>
   School of Biomedical Engineering - Research Day 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-03 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-03 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/03/school_of_biomedical_engineering___research_day_2019.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, Room 1020
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   The School of Biomedical Engineering is proud to present its 17th Annual Research Day Friday, May 3rd, 2019 in room 1020 of the Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building.  
From 8:30 am to 4:00 pm graduate students and guest speaker will present exciting and innovative Biomedical Engineering research work.  All presentations are open to the public.  Of special note are the presentations by Dr. Kullervo Hynynem and Dr. Jack Fa, this year's Distinguished Invited Speakers.  Please join us!
Please find the poster and full program​ at the Seminars&amp;Events Website:​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   102
  </id>
  <name>
   Writing Week for Grad Students
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-06 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-10 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/06/writing_week_for_grad_students.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   B400 Killam
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Writing Week is a special time in the spring term when graduate students often turn their attention to starting or completing major projects such as theses or publications. The Writing Centre staff meet with the group members each day at 9:00 to formulate plans. Writers leave and accomplish their tasks. They return at 4:00 to report on these efforts. Students find that the five-day process motivates them to get moving on their writing.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   103
  </id>
  <name>
   PeopleAdmin drop-in training sessions
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-07 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-07 15:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/07/peopleadmin_drop_in_training_sessions.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 2019, McCain Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   On April 29, Human Resources will launch a new recruitment system, PeopleAdmin. The roll-out of PeopleAdmin will be a phased approach, and will begin with all staff and grant-paid hiring. This new system will replace CareerBeacon for hiring staff, and the Academic Careers blog for faculty. It will also provide a new platform to facilitate the hiring processes for all employee groups. 
Drop-in training sessions for those who hire staff have been scheduled on the following dates:
Tuesday, May 7, 1:30 – 3:30 pm, Room 2019, McCain Building
Thursday, May 9, 10 am – 12 pm, Room 2019, McCain building
Tuesday, May 14, 10 am – 12 pm, Room 2019, McCain building
Wednesday, June 5, 2:30 – 4:30 pm, Room 221, Industrial Engineering &amp; Continuing Education Building
Training for those who hire faculty and/or part-time academics has been scheduled for Monday, May 6, 9:00 am – 11:30 am. Please contact Trisha.Aylward@dal.ca for more information or to sign up.
PeopleAdmin will provide applicants and our university community with an efficient recruitment process. It will also help us to collect better, more reliable data and will integrate with our central data systems, including Banner.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   104
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-08 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-08 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   105
  </id>
  <name>
   Innovation Rounds: Neurodegenerative eye and brain diseases: Where do we go from here?
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-09 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-09 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/09/innovation_rounds__neurodegenerative_eye_and_brain_diseases__where_do_we_go_from_here_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bethune Ballroom, 1st Fl. Bethune Building, VG Site, 1276 South Park St. Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Speaker: ​Dr. Alon Friedman, Founder and CEO of Emagix, Professor of Neuroscience and Dennis Chair in Epilepsy Research, Faculty of Medicine, Dalhousie University. 
Emagix is an early-stage biomedical company that has developed an algorithm-driven approach for diagnosis and treatment of patients with retinal and brain vascular injury.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   106
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation: Truro ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-10 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-10 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/10/spring_convocation__truro_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Langille Athletic Centre, Agricultural Campus, Truro
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Agriculture and Graduate Studies.
Ceremony will include retirement of the Dalhousie mace and welcoming of Dal's new ceremonial object.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   107
  </id>
  <name>
   University of King’s College Meet &amp; Greet Tour
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-11 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-11 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/11/university_of_king_s_college_meet___greet_tour.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Alumni Hall, University of King’s College
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Whether it’s performing with the King’s Theatrical Society, playing sports, going to formal meal or on wilderness hikes, discussing great books with your classmates and teachers, or learning to tell stories that matter to you and your community, there’s something at King’s for you.
At a meet-and-greet stop, you’ll meet current, former, and other future students and find out about campus life. Halifax attendees can stay for an optional campus tour after the event.
Our Halifax event will also be livestreamed on our Facebook page, if you can’t join us in person.”
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   108
  </id>
  <name>
   Caregiving: The Sandwich Generation (WEBINAR)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-13 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-13 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/13/caregiving__the_sandwich_generation__webinar_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Webinar
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   This webinar is being offered as part of the staff and faculty health and wellness program. Please regster here. 
Giving to work and family at the same time can be difficult for anyone, but for people in the sandwich generation—those who care for children and elderly parents—life can be especially demanding. Children need parents to look after their physical needs, take an interest in their activities, and give them emotional support and guidance. As parents age (and particularly if they become ill), they may need their children’s help with personal care, financial matters, and routine errands and tasks. This seminar will encourage participants to tune into important considerations in their lives with respect to caring for elderly family members, caring for children and grandchildren, as well as caring for themselves.
At the end of this seminar, participants will be able to do the following:
-Understand key concepts related to this phenomenon
 -Work through challenges
 -Implement self-care strategies
Instructions for online access to the seminar will be provided after you have registered.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   109
  </id>
  <name>
   PeopleAdmin drop-in training sessions
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-14 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-14 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/07/peopleadmin_drop_in_training_sessions.event.html/showing2.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 2019, McCain Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   On April 29, Human Resources will launch a new recruitment system, PeopleAdmin. The roll-out of PeopleAdmin will be a phased approach, and will begin with all staff and grant-paid hiring. This new system will replace CareerBeacon for hiring staff, and the Academic Careers blog for faculty. It will also provide a new platform to facilitate the hiring processes for all employee groups. 
Drop-in training sessions for those who hire staff have been scheduled on the following dates:
Tuesday, May 7, 1:30 – 3:30 pm, Room 2019, McCain Building
Thursday, May 9, 10 am – 12 pm, Room 2019, McCain building
Tuesday, May 14, 10 am – 12 pm, Room 2019, McCain building
Wednesday, June 5, 2:30 – 4:30 pm, Room 221, Industrial Engineering &amp; Continuing Education Building
Training for those who hire faculty and/or part-time academics has been scheduled for Monday, May 6, 9:00 am – 11:30 am. Please contact Trisha.Aylward@dal.ca for more information or to sign up.
PeopleAdmin will provide applicants and our university community with an efficient recruitment process. It will also help us to collect better, more reliable data and will integrate with our central data systems, including Banner.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   110
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-15 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-15 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   111
  </id>
  <name>
   NSERC Grant Writing Workshop 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-22 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-22 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/22/nserc_grant_writing_workshop_2019.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3089, 3rd floor, Kenneth Rowe
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   You are invited to a Panel Discussion on “How to Write a Strong NSERC Discovery and RTI Grant Application”. The session will be led by Laurent Kreplak (Associate Dean Research, Faculty of Science). Along with panelists from the Faculties of Science, Computer Science, and Engineering, Laurent will provide an overview of the Discovery and RTI Grants, key features to remember when writing, and four rounds of Q&amp;A: CCV, proposal, HQP plan, and RTI. The discussion will be captured and made widely available in a “Tips and Tricks” document to all Faculty.
Date: Wednesday, May 22nd, 2019
 Time: 10 - 11:30 am
 Location: Room 3089, 3rd floor, Kenneth Rowe Building and by video stream.
Refreshments will be served.
Please RSVP to Keerthi Baruah at keerthi.baruah@dal.ca. 
This event is being organized by the Office of Research Services​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   112
  </id>
  <name>
   Beyond GDP: International Experiences, Canada's Options
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-23 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-24 15:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/23/beyond_gdp__international_experiences__canada_s_options.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Weldon 104 on May 23, University Hall on May 24
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Join us on May 23-24, 2019 for a two-day workshop that brings together Canadian and international academics, policy-makers, NGOs, and members of the public to share knowledge about “beyond GDP” measurement initiatives and discuss next steps forward. We have an exciting program with presentations by many leading researchers and practitioners, including a keynote talk by John Helliwell, professor emeritus in economics at the University of British Columbia and lead author of the annual World Happiness Report. Concluding sessions will discuss next steps in Canada and develop recommendations for governments. Event is free. Registration required.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   113
  </id>
  <name>
   Ramadan Iftar
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-24 20:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-24 20:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/24/ramadan_iftar.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie International Centre, 1246 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ramadan Kareem to all of our Muslim community members who will begin the month of fasting on May 6th! We invite you all to join us in a campus Iftar (breaking of the fast) on May 24, 2019 at 8:30pm. We will begin with a short welcome, followed by Maghrib Prayer at 8:50pm, followed by a delicious Iftar and potluck catered by Chef Abod Cafe &amp; Catering. We encourage folks to bring a dish to share for the potluck. Everyone is welcome to join us as we connect over delicious food, inspiring words, and community.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   114
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation - Morning ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-27 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-27 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/27/spring_convocation___morning_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Medicine and Graduate Studies.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   115
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation - Morning ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-28 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-28 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/28/spring_convocation___morning_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Architecture &amp; Planning, Dentistry and Graduate Studies.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   116
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation - Morning ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-29 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-29 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/29/spring_convocation___morning_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Engineering and Graduate Studies.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   117
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation - Morning ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-30 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-30 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/30/spring_convocation___morning_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Health and Graduate Studies
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   118
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation - Morning ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-31 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-05-31 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/31/spring_convocation___morning_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Science and Graduate Studies.
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   119
  </id>
  <name>
   13th Annual Lebanese Cedar Festival
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-05-30 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-02 22:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/04/30/13th_annual_lebanese_cedar_festival.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   111 Clayton Park Drive
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Bring your family &amp; friends and come savour the sights, sounds, and tastes of EVERYTHING LEBANESE.
Always FREE ADMISSION
Enjoy a fun-filled weekend of world class entertainment, authentic Lebanese cuisine, live musical and cultural shows, children’s fun play area, mouth-watering pastries, great cultural displays and much, much more!

This is our opportunity to show the world our Lebanese culture and simply put, our passion for life. Participate in FREE events throughout the festival that will bring you along for the ride.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   120
  </id>
  <name>
   Spring Convocation - Morning ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-01 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-01 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/01/spring_convocation___morning_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Rebecca Cohn Auditorium, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Ceremony for graduates in the Faculties of Management and Graduate Studies
  </description>
  <cost>
   n/a
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   121
  </id>
  <name>
   Dalhousie Commuter Challenge - June 2-9
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-02 07:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-09 23:45:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/02/dalhousie_commuter_challenge___june_2_9.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie University (All Campuses)
  </location>
  <category>
   Health and Wellness
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie University is going to be participating in a week-long Commuter Challenge. 
The Commuter Challenge encourages Canadians to leave their cars at home and reward those who walk, cycle, carpool, and take public transit to work or school. This year the challenge runs from Saturday, June 2nd to Sunday, June 9th. 
Visit https://www.dal.ca/dept/sustainability/smart-trip/Events/CommuterChallenge.html for more details on how to register.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   122
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Pharmacology
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-03 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-03 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/03/phd_defence___department_of_pharmacology.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Yan Burkovskiy, PhD candidate from the Department of Pharmacology, will be defending their thesis entitled "Cannabinoid 2 Receptor-Based Modulation of the Immune Response in Experimental Models of CNS Injury" on Monday, June 3rd, at 1:00 p​​m.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   123
  </id>
  <name>
   ACENET Parallel Computing School
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-04 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-07 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/04/acenet_parallel_computing_school.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   University of Kings College
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   This three-and-a-half day Parallel Computing Summer School includes topics such as general parallel computing, I/O and data movement, schedulers and “embarrassingly parallel” jobs, OpenMP, Message Passing Interface (MPI) and GPGPU-CUDA. The school is designed for participants familiar with the Linux command line and who have some level of programming experience. Completion of the ACENET Basics Series, or equivalent experience, is strongly recommended. The mornings will consist of lectures, with the afternoons following a lab format, where participants will be given exercises, or can bring specific problems to instructors related to their research.
  </description>
  <cost>
   $40
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   124
  </id>
  <name>
   IE Seminar: Optimization Framework for Natural Gas Storage Assets Subject to Price Uncertainty
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-05 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-05 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/05/ie_seminar__optimization_framework_for_natural_gas_storage_assets_subject_to_price_uncertainty.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   MA 310, 5269 Morris Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Natural gas offers a clean and efficient fuel-burning method of power generation and heating. North America, specifically, features a sprawling network of natural gas pipelines and storage facilities that bring natural gas (NG) from source to customer. Like many commodities (oil, electricity, etc.), the price of NG is subject to uncertainty. Natural gas storage assets can allow marketing companies to make money by injecting or withdrawing gas at opportune moments. Even simple contracts; however, involve large numbers of decisions and constraints that must be considered. Furthermore, because of the financial nature of storage decisions, it is desirable to measure or include risk in the decision-making process. This work presents optimization framework that serves as a decision support tool for natural gas storage assets. Mixed-integer-programming models are presented for two types of storage decisions: forward and cash. Model framework includes constraints that consider the impact of asset inventory on injection and withdrawal rates. Including said constraints is found to be essential in determining feasible injection and withdrawal decisions when assets are subject to inventory ratcheting. For both cash and forward decisions, Stochastic, Robust and Distributionally Robust Optimization alternatives are presented to account for risk. Parameterization of the risk-management alternatives allows for a user to obtain tactical plans for storage assets while considering varying levels of risk tolerance and averseness.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   125
  </id>
  <name>
   Transportation Trip Planning - 2019 Bike Week Event
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-06 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-06 12:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/06/transportation_trip_planning___2019_bike_week_event.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Killam Memorial Library, 6225 University Avenue, Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Cycling instructor Scott MacPhee from the Office of Sustainability scheduling one-on-one 30-45 minute appointments at Killam Memorial Library ​with people interested in establishing a cycling route to get from their home to work, school, and other accommodations.​
The number of participants available for this event is flexible and can be scheduled by contacting Scott MacPhee at rethink@dal.ca.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   126
  </id>
  <name>
   Elisabeth Mann Borgese Ocean Lecture - The "Blue Revolution": Challenges and Opportunities
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-07 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-07 20:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/07/elisabeth_mann_borgese_ocean_lecture___the__blue_revolution___challenges_and_opportunities.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 105 Weldon Law Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The 15th annual EMB Ocean Lecture features keynote speaker: Ms Renée Sauvé, Acting Director General, External Relations Directorate, Fisheries and Oceans Canada discussing Canada's recent experience of the "Blue Revolution".  Responses will be provided from the perspectives of conservation, biodiversity, environment and social justice by panel members: Dr Ratana Chuenpagdee, Director, Too Big To Ignore Partnership, MUN, Dr Susanna Fuller, Senior Project Manager, Oceans North, and Ms Sigrid Kuehnemund, Vice President, Ocean Conservation, WWF-Canada.  Reception to follow.  All welcome.
IOI-Canada is pleased to present this World Oceans Day public event in partnership with Canadian Wildlife Federation, Oceans North, Too Big to Ignore and WWF-Canada.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   127
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Civil and Resource Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-10 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-10 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/10/phd_defence___department_of_civil_and_resource_engineering.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Ehsan Nasirikhaneghah​, PhD candidate from the Department of Civil and Resource Engineering, will be defending their thesis entitled "Experimental and Numerical Study of In-Plane and Out-Of-Plane Behaviour of Masonry Infilled Rc Frames​" on Monday, June 10th, at 9:00 a​​​​m.​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   128
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Pathology
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-11 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-11 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/11/phd_defence___department_of_pharmacology.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Qianni Hu, PhD candidate from the Department of Pathology, will be defending their thesis entitled "Extracellular Mitochondria Released from Liver Ischemia Reperfusion Injury act as Alarmins to Evoke Innate Immune System and Trigger Inflammation​" on Tuesday, June 11th, at 9​:30 a​​​​m.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   129
  </id>
  <name>
   Microbiome Seminars
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-12 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-12 11:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/12/microbiome_seminars.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3-H1, Tupper Medical Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Two seminars sponsored by DalMUG &amp; Centre for Comparative Genomics &amp; Evolutionary Bioinformatics:
Dr. Laura Sycuro, University of Calgary:  "Defining the vaginal microbiome with genome-resolved metagenomics: have we opened Pandora's box?", and,
Dr. Jennifer Stearns, McMaster University:  "Our friends the bifidobacteria: molecular and culture based stories from the infant gut microbiome"
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   130
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Faculty of Computer Science
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-13 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-13 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/13/phd_defence___faculty_of_computer_science.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Behrouz Haji Soleimani, PhD candidate from the Faculty of Computer Science, will be defending their thesis entitled "Learning Embeddings for Text and Images from Structure of the Data ​" on Thursday, June 13th, at 9:00 a​​​​m.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   131
  </id>
  <name>
   Primary Health Care Research Day
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-17 08:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-17 08:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/17/primary_health_care_research_day.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Collaborative Health Education Building (CHEB), 5793 University Ave.​​
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   Primary Health Care Research Day is an opportunity for learners, decision makers, citizens, clinicians and researchers from a variety of disciplines to come together and celebrate primary health care research in Nova Scotia and across Canada.  Primary Health Care Research Day is presented by Building Research for Integrated Primary Healthcare (BRIC NS).  BRIC NS is ​Nova Scotia's Strategy for Patient-Oriented Research (SPOR) Primary and Integrated Health Care Innovations (PIHCI) Network.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Clinicians, Health Professionals, Decision Makers and Researchers: $130
Medical Residents: $75
Students, Patients, Caregivers and Citizens: $50
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   132
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-19 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-19 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing5.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   133
  </id>
  <name>
   Angus Macpherson Retirement Party - Faculty of Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-20 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-20 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/20/angus_macpherson_retirement_party___faculty_of_engineering_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   T-Room, Sexton Campus
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Faculty of Engineering technician Angus Macpherson has announced his upcoming retirement after 50+ years with the Faculty.  Friends and colleagues are invited to drop in and say their good byes​ and help celebrate Angus' big day.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   134
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Chemistry
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-24 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-24 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/24/phd_defence___department_of_chemistry.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Luc Leblanc, PhD candidate from the Department of Chemistry​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Development and Applications of Composite and Low-Cost Approaches in Molecular Crystal Structure Prediction" on Monday, June 24th, at 9:30 a​​​​m.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   135
  </id>
  <name>
   MSSU NS Bridge Event
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-25 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-25 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/25/general_registration_is_now_open_for_the_mssu_ns_bridge_event.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bluenose Ballroom, Hotel Halifax (formerly Delta Halifax), 1990 Barrington St, Halifax, NS
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   The Maritime SPOR SUPPORT Unit NS Bridge Event is a bi-annual gathering that brings together health care decision-makers and providers, researchers, patients and the public, who spend a half-day in facilitated group discussions about priority health topics. If you have experience in one of the following priority topics, join the discussion and help to shape future research in this area.
Priority Topics
Our team has worked closely with colleagues at the Nova Scotia Department of Health and Wellness, the Nova Scotia Health Authority (NSHA), and IWK Health Centre to identify the following seven priority health topics for discussion:​
1.  How do we better prepare and facilitate transitions of care for pediatric patients with chronic conditions?
2.  Development of a framework to evaluate the progress/ success of the implementation of the NS presumed consent policy for organ donation.
3. How do we improve patient flow – both into and out of the hospital (from home to hospital, community-based care, assisted living)?
4.  What is best-evidence around the medical management of chronic symptoms that are not tied to a specific diagnosis? What is the feasibility of the identified model(s) and application of this in Nova Scotia?
5.  What is the best model of collaborative mental health care delivery? How can we effectively leverage existing community resources to fill transition in care gaps?
6. How can we decrease vaping activity among youth in Nova Scotia?
7.  How do childhood development indices (school readiness-EDI; middle years development-MDI) relate to healthcare utilization in Nova Scotia, and how do these relationships differ across neighborhood clusters?
To register, visit: http://events.constantcontact.com/register/event?llr=ryzppguab&amp;oeidk=a07egdpffcy0b2a0f02
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   136
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-26 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-26 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing6.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   137
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Mathematics and Statistics
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-06-28 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-06-28 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/28/phd_defence___department_of_mathematics_and_statistics.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Melissa Huggan, PhD candidate from the Department of Mathematics and Statistics​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Approximation Tools in Combinatorial Game Theory " on Friday, June 28th, at 1:30 pm.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   138
  </id>
  <name>
   HR/DPMG Growing Communities Series - Community Garden
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-02 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-02 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/25/hr_dpmg_growing_communities_series___community_garden.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Community Garden, located on Henry Street behind the Computer Science building (near the intersection of Henry Street and University Avenue).
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Hello everyone!
We are looking for volunteers to help out at the Dalhousie Urban Garden.
Partnering with Dalhousie Urban Garden Society (DUGS) and the Loaded Ladle, the Growing Communities Event Series is excited to announce a new initiative to address food scarcity on campus! We are looking for volunteers to help with the Community Garden, located on Henry Street behind the Computer Science building (near the intersection of Henry Street and University Avenue). We will donate all fresh produce to the Loaded Ladle in support of their “free meals program” for students.
If you are interested, please fill out the sign up sheet (further info is also located on the signup sheet!). Based on interest, we hope to continue this initiative in the coming years.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   139
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-03 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-03 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing7.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   140
  </id>
  <name>
   Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology MSc Thesis Defence
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-04 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-04 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/04/department_of_biochemistry___molecular_biology_msc_thesis_defence.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room C264, Collaborative Health Education Building (Halifax, NS) and Room 221, DMNB (Saint John, NB)
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   M.Sc. Thesis Defence, Tyler MacDonald
B.Sc. (Hons.) Dalhousie University
 
“MECHANISTIC INSIGHT INTO THE PROLACTIN-/ANDROGEN-INDUCIBLE CARBOXYPEPTIDASE-D AND EDD E3 UBIQUITIN LIGASE GENES IN TRIPLE-NEGATIVE BREAST CANCER”
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   141
  </id>
  <name>
   HR/DPMG Growing Communities Series - Community Garden
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-09 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-09 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/06/25/hr_dpmg_growing_communities_series___community_garden.event.html/showing2.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Community Garden, located on Henry Street behind the Computer Science building (near the intersection of Henry Street and University Avenue).
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Hello everyone!
We are looking for volunteers to help out at the Dalhousie Urban Garden.
Partnering with Dalhousie Urban Garden Society (DUGS) and the Loaded Ladle, the Growing Communities Event Series is excited to announce a new initiative to address food scarcity on campus! We are looking for volunteers to help with the Community Garden, located on Henry Street behind the Computer Science building (near the intersection of Henry Street and University Avenue). We will donate all fresh produce to the Loaded Ladle in support of their “free meals program” for students.
If you are interested, please fill out the sign up sheet (further info is also located on the signup sheet!). Based on interest, we hope to continue this initiative in the coming years.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   142
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-10 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-10 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing8.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   143
  </id>
  <name>
   Earth and Environmental Sciences Seminar - Monitoring reservoir response to earthquakes and fluid extraction, Salton Sea geothermal field, California
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-11 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-11 12:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/11/earth_and_environmental_sciences_seminar___monitoring_reservoir_response_to_earthquakes_and_fluid_extraction__salton_sea_geothermal_field__california.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Gordon Riley Room LSC3652 Oceanography
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Monitoring reservoir response to earthquakes and fluid extraction, Salton Sea geothermal field, California
Dr. Taka’aki Taira
Associate Research Seismologist
UC Berkeley Seismology Lab, USA
Continuous monitoring of in situ reservoir responses to stress transients provides insights into the evolution of geothermal reservoirs. By exploiting the stress dependence of seismic velocity changes, we investigate the temporal evolution of the reservoir stress state of the Salton Sea geothermal field (SSGF), California. We find that the SSGF experienced a number of sudden velocity reductions (~0.035 to 0.25%) that are most likely caused by openings of fractures due to dynamic stress transientsfrom local and regional earthquakes. Depths of velocity changes are estimated to be about 0.5 to 1.5 km, similar to the depths of the injection and production wells. We derive an empirical in situ stress sensitivity of seismic velocity changes by relating velocity changes to dynamic stresses. We also observe systematic velocity reductions (0.04 to 0.05%) during earthquake swarms in mid-November 2009 and late-December 2010. On the basis of volumetric static and dynamic stress changes, the expected velocity reductions from the largest earthquakes with magnitude ranging from 3 to 4 in these swarms are less than 0.02%, which suggests that these earthquakes are likely not responsible for the velocity changes observed during the swarms. Instead, we argue thatvelocity reductions may have been induced by poroelastic opening of fractures due to aseismic deformation. We also observe a long-term velocity increase (~0.04%/year) that is most likely due to poroelastic contraction caused by the geothermal production. Our observations demonstrate that seismic interferometry provides insights into in situ reservoir response to stress changes.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   144
  </id>
  <name>
   Agricultural Campus Flag Raising &amp; Strawberry Social
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-12 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-12 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/12/agricultural_campus_flag_raising___strawberry_social.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Amphitheatre, Agricultural Campus
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Join the Agricultural campus in celebrating Pride Week with a Flag Raising in the amphitheatre!
A strawberry social will also be included in the festivities. Everyone is invited to join us!
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   145
  </id>
  <name>
   Truro Pride Parade
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-13 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-13 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/13/truro_pride_parade.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Parade will begin at Colchester Legion Stadium, 14 Lorne St
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Join the Dalhousie contingent on the Agricultural Campus to march in Truro's Pride Parade! Their tractor and hay wagon will be transformed into Rocky's chariot for event.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   146
  </id>
  <name>
   Panel on the value-added food sector with Canadian Senators
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-16 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-16 15:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/16/july_16th_panel_on_the_value_added_food_sector_with_canadian_senators.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Lord Dalhousie Room, Hicks Bldg., Room 141
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   On behalf of the Standing Committee on Agriculture and Forestry, Senator Diane F. Griffin, chair, Senator Colin Deacon, and Senator Stan Kutcher, invite you to join them as they discuss the committee’s study on how the value-added sector can be more competitive in global markets.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   147
  </id>
  <name>
   IE Seminar - Robust Gear Pitting Detection for Condition Monitoring of Gearbox
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-17 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-17 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/17/ie_seminar___robust_gear_pitting_detection_for_condition_monitoring_of_gearbox.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   5269 Morris Street; Room 310.
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The gear pairs in a gearbox is a source of vibration and noise. Among the various flaws commonly encountered in case of gear tooth, the pitting on the tooth surface is a common one. This talk will discuss the reasons for the vibration arising out of the gear-meshing and discuss recent work at the Vibration Research lab, IIT Delhi to explore robust gear pitting detection methods considering the associated dynamics and novel signal processing to extract the features. As the pitting level increases, the amplitude and frequency modulation characteristics are influenced. By processing the time domain data, the correlation of the future measured vibration to the baseline healthy condition data is quantified through a proposed correlation coefficient of residual vibration signal. Based on many run-to-failure test data on a specially designed gearbox life test rig, it is found that the pitting detection using this parameter gives significantly better results. In another work on a wind turbine gearbox, the dynamics of the planetary stage is modeled and methods to detect damage (a fatigue crack) on the planet gear tooth using vibration data are proposed.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   148
  </id>
  <name>
   Community Day on the Agricultural Campus
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-18 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-18 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/18/community_day_on_the_agricultural_campus.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie Agricultural Campus
62 Cumming Drive
Bible Hill
  </location>
  <category>
  </category>
  <description>
   All of our doors are open to you to come and explore our beautiful campus.
Join us for a day of fun, exploration and surprise. Hop on one of our tractors, partake in our BBQ, and enjoy an ice cream treat while learning about the range of work we do to feed and protect our world.
Visit us rain or shine!
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   149
  </id>
  <name>
   Department of Earth and Environmental Sciences Seminar  - Super-Resolution Imaging: From Subsurface Fracture Detection to Cancer Characterization
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-19 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-19 12:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/19/department_of_earth_and_environmental_sciences_seminar____super_resolution_imaging__from_subsurface_fracture_detection_to_cancer_characterization.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Riley Room,  3655 LSC, Oceanography Wing Dalhousie University
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Dr. Lianjie Huang
 Senior Scientist 5
 Los Alamos National Laboratory, USA

“Super-Resolution Imaging: From Subsurface Fracture Detection to Cancer Characterization”
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   150
  </id>
  <name>
   Halifax Pride Parade - Dal Viewing Area
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-20 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-20 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/20/halifax_pride_parade___dal_viewing_area.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Medjuck Architecture Building (5410 Spring Garden Road)
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Halifax Pride Parade will start at 1:00pm from Valour Way
DPMG will be hosting the Dal viewing area in front of the Medjuck Architecture Building (5410 
 Spring Garden Road, next to the Halifax Central Library). Join in the fun from 12 - 1:30pm for button making, face painting and freezies!  Everyone is welcome to join us!
A limited number of Dal Pride hats will be at the viewing station.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   151
  </id>
  <name>
   Pop-Up Loose Parts Playground
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-22 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-22 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/22/pop_up_loose_parts_playground.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Halifax Commons (beside the playground)
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Dalhousie University's Physical Literacy in the Early Years (PLEY) project research team is hosting a free loose parts pop-up playground event. This is a free public event aimed at children aged 2 to 12 years. Bring your children to the Halifax Commons and come and play with us!
Please see our website (https://playoutsidens.com/events/) to register for this event, and for more information on other events as part of our "Summer of PLEY" series.

 This event is supported by the following agencies: Dalhousie University's Healthy Populations Institute, the Dalhousie Medical Research Foundation (Picchione Visiting Scholars Series), and the Nova Scotia Health Research Foundation (Knowledge Sharing Support Award).
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   152
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Physics and Atmospheric Science
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-23 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-23 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/23/phd_defence___department_of_physics_and_atmospheric_science.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Samuel Baldwin, PhD candidate from the Department of Physics and Atmospheric Science​​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Structural Variation and Enzymatic Susceptibility of Collagen Fibrils Extracted from Native and Overloaded Tail Tendons​" on Tuesday, July 23rd, at 10:00 am.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   153
  </id>
  <name>
   IE Seminar - Predicting the Ambulance Offload Delay Problem Using A Hybrid Decision Tree Model
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-24 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-24 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/24/ie_seminar___predicting_the_ambulance_offload_delay_problem_using_a_hybrid_decision_tree_model.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   MA 310, 5269 Morris Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Introduction: Ambulance offload delay (AOD) is a growing health care concern in Canada. It refers to the delay in transferring an ambulance patient to a hospital emergency department (ED) due to ED congestion. It can negatively affect the ability of the ambulance service to respond to future calls and reduces the efficiency of the system, when the delay is significant.
Methods: Using integrated historical data from a partnering hospital and an Emergency Medical Services (EMS) provider, we developed a decision-support tool using a hybrid decision tree model to predict the severity of AOD occurring within 1 to 5 hours in an EMS system. The primary objective of this study is to provide a prediction model for the AOD states based on the current system status as well as hours of the day and day of the week, so that the decision makers can activate proactive interventions at different states of the system to mitigate AOD.
Results: Various prediction models were developed based on different prediction focuses and periods to be tailored to the client's needs. The prediction models perform relatively well with accuracy rates of 60%-75%, 69%-83%, and 91%-95%, with respect to different prediction settings. Furthermore, we aim to advance the application of predictive modeling in health care. This research demonstrates a novel hybrid decision tree method that being applied with administrative data in the health care setting. A naïve Bayes classifier was employed first to remove the noisy training observations before the decision tree induction. This hybrid decision tree algorithm was tested against the basic classification and regression tree (CART) algorithm, using classification accuracy, precision, sensitivity and specificity analysis. The results indicate that the hybrid algorithm outperforms the traditional algorithm by an average accuracy improvement of 2.44%.
Conclusions: It is anticipated that the prediction model for AOD produced from this study will be directly transferable. It can be generalized to other EMS systems with a similar operational setting where ambulance offload is impacted by ED congestion. ​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   154
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Chemical Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-26 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-26 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/26/phd_defence___department_of_chemical_engineering.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Jie Yang, PhD candidate from the Department of Chemical Engineering, will be defending their thesis entitled "Hydrothermal Liquefaction of Biomass and Process Intensification​​" on Friday, July 26th, at 1:00 pm.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   155
  </id>
  <name>
   Analysis and mining of complex network: an overview of our current research
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-30 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-30 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/07/30/analysis_and_mining_of_complex_network__an_overview_of_our_current_research.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   CIBC Auditorium, Goldberg Computer Science Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Abstract:
 In this presentation, I will describe our current research on the analysis and mining of complex networks. The representation of data and knowledge as a graph allows us to take advantage of a more expressive "relational" representation of data compared to the usual propositional attribute-value representation employed in data mining. The graph allows objects and the relationship among them to be naturally represented. The presentation will focus primarily on network-based, supervised, semi-supervised, and unsupervised learning techniques developed in our group.I will comment on some of our articles on these topics, as well as some applications and future work.
Speaker Bio:
 Alneu de Andrade Lopes holds a master's degree in Computer Science from the University of São Paulo (1995) and a Ph.D. in Computer Science from the University of Porto (2001). Currently, he is Professor at the University of São Paulo. His research is in the field of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, mainly in the following subjects: Data Mining and Complex Network Mining.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   156
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-07-31 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-07-31 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing11.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   157
  </id>
  <name>
   Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology MSc Thesis Defence
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-01 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-01 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/01/department_of_biochemistry___molecular_biology_msc_thesis_defence.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room C264, Collaborative Health Education Building (CHEB), (Halifax, NS) and Room 221, DMNB (Saint John, NB)
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   MSc Thesis Defence, Christopher Fetter
“Exploring Catalysis in the Mandelate Racemase Subgroup of the Enolase Superfamily: Subtle Differences in the Catalytic Machinery”​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   158
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of English
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-06 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-06 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/06/phd_defence___department_of_english.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 430, The Goldberg Computer Science Building, 6050 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Mark Diachyshyn, PhD candidate from the Department of English, will be defending their thesis entitled " 'Their Voice Is Music To My Ear' The Role of Women in the Work of John Thelwall" on Tuesday,  August 6th, at 9:30 a​m.​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   159
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Psychology and Neuroscience
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-07 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-07 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/07/phd_defence___department_of_psychology_and_neuroscience.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Sarah Kraeytner, PhD candidate from the Department of Psychology and Neuroscience​​​, will be defending their thesis entitled "​Neural Mechanisms of Motor Imagery and the Nature of Imagery-Based Skill Acquisition" on Wednesday, August 7th, at 9:00 am.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   160
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Medical Neuroscience
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-08 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-08 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/08/phd_defence___department_of_medical_neuroscience.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 430, The Goldberg Computer Science Building, 6050 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Drew Debay, PhD candidate from the Department of Medical Neuroscience, will be defending their thesis entitled "Molecular Neuroimaging in Alzheimer's Disease: Targeting Butyrylcholinesterase for Positron Emission Tomography (PET) and Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography (SPECT) Imaging of the Brain" on Thursday, August 8th, at 9:00 am.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   161
  </id>
  <name>
   The power of PLEY: Why kids need to play every day
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-10 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-10 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/10/the_power_of_pley__why_kids_need_to_play_every_day.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Halifax Central Public Library
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Children spend less time outdoors and have more physical and mental health challenges than previous generations. Dalhousie University's Physical Literacy in the Early Years (PLEY) research team, in partnership with internationally-renowned outdoor play researcher, Dr. Mariana Brussoni, will share how outdoor play - with its risks - is essential for lifelong health and wellness.
Please see our website (https://playoutsidens.com/events/) to register for this event, and for more information on other events as part of our "Summer of PLEY" series.

 For more information on our key speaker, please visit the following sites:

 Website: https://brussoni.lab

 Twitter: @mbrussoni

 This event is funded through the Dalhousie Medical Research Foundation's Picchione Visiting Scholars Series, and supported through a Knowledge Sharing Support Award from the Nova Scotia Health Research Foundation.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   162
  </id>
  <name>
   Dalhousie Muslim Student Association Eid Al-adha BBQ
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-12 17:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-12 21:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/08/dalhousie_muslim_student_association_eid_al_adha_bbq_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   The Quad
  </location>
  <category>
   Religious &amp; Spiritual
  </category>
  <description>
   This is a BBQ event meant to celebrate the islamic festival of Eid al adha 
The event is student centered and is the first of its kind in recent years to be held follwing the ratification of the DMSA(DAL MUSLIM STUENT ASSOCAITION ) by the DSU this summer after it has long been inactive.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   163
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of English
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-13 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-13 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/13/phd_defence___department_of_english.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Brandi Estey-Burtt, PhD candidate from the Department of English​​​, will be defending their thesis entitled "When the Messiah Comes: The Postsecular Messianic in Contemporary Literature​" on Tuesday, August 13th, at 1:30 pm.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   164
  </id>
  <name>
   Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology MSc Thesis Defence
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-14 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-14 12:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/14/department_of_biochemistry___molecular_biology_msc_thesis_defence.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room C264, Collaborative Health Education Building (CHEB), (Halifax, NS) and Room 266, (DMNB) (Saint John, NB)
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   MSc Thesis Defence, Luke E Hattie
 
“A novel model of elevated mitochondrial cholesterol and the consequences for mitochondrial function”​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   165
  </id>
  <name>
   Data Centre Firewall Upgrade Project - IT outages scheduled for August 18
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-18 05:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-18 08:15:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/18/data_centre_firewall_upgrade_project___it_outages_scheduled_for_august_18.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Campus wide
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Due to issues on a previous attempt, Information Technology Services will be upgrading the main data centre firewall again on Sunday, August 18.. This upgrade is part of our continuing improvement of our network under the University key strategic initiative in Section 5.0
“Infrastructure and Planning”. 
​What is the impact?
There will be an outage impacting some critical business activities during the migration to the new firewall. Testing will be conducted prior to the implementation of the new firewall as well as after the migration to ensure success. 
This outage will affect access to Dalhousie resources and services hosted wholly or partially in the Dalhousie Halifax campus data centre
including:

Office 365 (Mail, OneDrive, ...)
Dal.ca, my.Dal, and DalOnline
Banner and other enterprise systems
DALCARD
  </description>
  <cost>
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   166
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Industrial Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-19 10:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-19 10:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/19/phd_defence___department_of_industrial_engineering.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Muhammad Nadeem, PhD candidate from the Department of Industrial Engineering​​​, will be defending their thesis entitled "​Contributions to the Study of Spraying Operations in the Context of Sustainable Agriculture" on Monday, August 19th, at 10:30 am.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   167
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Mechanical Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-20 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-20 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/20/phd_defence___department_of_mechanical_engineering.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Davide De Cicco, PhD candidate from the Department of Mechanical Engineering​, will be defending their thesis entitled "In-Depth Understanding of the Stability Response of a Novel 3d Fiber-Metal Laminate under Axial Impact Loading​" on Tuesday, August 20th, at 9:00 am.​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   168
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-21 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-21 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/21/phd_defence___department_of_biochemistry_and_molecular_biology.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Kenneth d'Souza, PhD candidate from the Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Autotaxin is Nutritionally Regulated and Alters Mitochondrial Function in Obesity-Induced Insulin Resistance​" on Wednesday, August 21st, at 9:30 am.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   169
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Faculty of Computer Science
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-22 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-22 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/22/phd_defence___faculty_of_computer_science.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 430, The Goldberg Computer Science Building, 6050 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Sima Sharifirad, PhD candidate from the Faculty of Computer Science​, will be defending their thesis entitled "NLP and Machine Learning Techniques ​to Detect Online Harassment on Social Networking Platforms" on Thursday, August 22nd, at 1:30 pm.​​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   170
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Faculty of Law
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-26 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-26 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/26/phd_defence___faculty_of_law.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 430, The Goldberg Computer Science Building, 6050 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Colin Jackson, PhD candidate from the Faculty of Law​​​​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Into the 'Vortex of Legal Precision': Access to Justice, Complexity, and the Canadian Tax System​" on Monday, August 26th, at 9:30 am.​​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   171
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-27 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-27 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/27/phd_defence___department_of_electrical_and_computer_engineering.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Javad Hoseyni, PhD candidate from the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering​, will be defending their thesis entitled "Smart Antenna Pattern Beamforming in the Design of Modulation, Coding and Multiple Access Techniques" on Tuesday, August 27th, at 1:30 p​m.​​​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   172
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-28 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-28 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing14.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   173
  </id>
  <name>
   Dal Bookstore Community Night
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-29 17:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-29 20:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/29/dal_bookstore_community_night.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dal Bookstore
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   The Dal Bookstore invites all students to get a jump on the new school year by attending our annual Community Night -- your night to get your university textbooks and supplies and beat the back-to-class rush.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   174
  </id>
  <name>
   Celebrating Creoledom with Black Loyalists: Our History, Our Culture, Our Heritage
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-08-31 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-08-31 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/08/31/celebrating_creoledom_with_black_loyalists__our_history__our_culture__our_heritage.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dal Club - Dalhousie University Club
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   2019 Arthur Porter Symposium, will be presented by Creole Heritage Association Association Canada and proudly sponsored by Dalhousie University and University of Kings College.  Distinguished Speakers:  Prof. Dr. Afua D. Cooper; Prof. Dr. Nemata A. Blyden-Bickersteth; Ambassador Yvette Stevens; Prof. Dr. Handel Kashope Wright; Prof. Dr. Jerry Cline-Bailey, Prof. Dr. Jonathan E. H. Wilson; Prof. Dr. Vincent Simedoh; Prof. David Divine.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   175
  </id>
  <name>
   CELEBRATING CREOLEDOM: Remembering the Black Loyalists in the Year of Jubilee. (1972-2019)
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-01 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-01 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/01/celebrating_creoledom__remembering_the_black_loyalists_in_the_year_of_jubilee___1972_2019_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Cathedral Church of All Saints (All Saints Cathedral) 1330 Cathedral Lane Halifax, NS B3H 2Z1
  </location>
  <category>
   Religious &amp; Spiritual
  </category>
  <description>
   The historic connection
An increasing number of individuals have shown interest in the historical and cultural ties between Freetown, Sierra Leone; Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Jamaica. This has taken the form of lectures and discussions, research and publications, trans-Atlantic visits and even the retracing of long-severed family connections.  Historically, Nova Scotia is known as the birthplace of the Creoles in Sierra Leone as Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.  Halifax was the departure point for the groups of liberated slaves and Black Loyalists who sailed  Freetown, Sierra Leone in January in 1792. Fifteen ships left Halifax carrying about 1,196 passengers.  In March, they arrived on the shores of the West African colony owned by a British philanthropic organization called the Sierra Leone Company.  The Nova Scotia Settlers built houses, established churches, started families and founded the City of Freetown.  This much-overdue awakening culminated in the 2016 when Krio Descendants Union Canada (KDU Canada) launched the 1st Journey to Nova Scotia with a 5 day celebration. The Journey to Nova Scotia in 2016 was a remarkable event which has called for a repeat of the event on Sunday, September 1, 2019.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   176
  </id>
  <name>
   @Cat Seminar
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-03 14:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-03 15:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/03/_cat_seminar.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   #319 Colloquium Room Chase Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Speaker: Robert Paré (Dalhousie University) 
Title: Kleisli Double Categories 
Abstract: 
I will review the theory of monads and their Kleisli categories. Then I'll argue that taking a double category point of view sheds some light on their morphisms and 2-cells.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   177
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-04 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-04 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing15.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   178
  </id>
  <name>
   Registrar's Office Pop-up Shop
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-05 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-05 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/05/registrar_s_office_pop_up_shop.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Howe Hall
  </location>
  <category>
  </category>
  <description>
   The start of a new academic year is an exciting and busy time on campus, and the Registrar's Office is at the heart of the hustle and bustle. Whether we're helping students manage their academic profile, advising faculty members on academic regulations, or supporting staff in navigating the university's processes, the Registrar's Office is a key part of the running of the university and an essential component of what makes Dal a great place to study and work. 

This year, we're excited to be launching a new initiative which will bring our service out on the road and directly to you!
For the first two weeks of term, watch out for our Registrar's Office Pop-up Shops around campus. Posted at locations around our Halifax sites, you'll have the opportunity to meet our friendly RO staff, find out more about our service, and ask us any burning questions you may have.
Students who visit us can also enter our prize draw, which will test your Dal knowledge for a chance to win a fantastic grand prize of an iPad! 

We hope to get the chance to meet as many students, faculty, and staff as possible at our Pop-up Shops around campus, but if you can't get out to see us then, remember that you can visit us at any of our service centre locations, or the Henry Hicks building, to find out what we can do for you.
​We look forward to seeing you soon.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   179
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Defence - School of Nursing
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-06 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-06 09:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/06/phd_defence___school_of_nursing.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3107, The Mona Campbell Building, 1459 LeMarchant Street
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Faculty of Graduate Studies wishes to announce Heather Mingo, PhD candidate from the School of Nursing​​​​, will be defending their thesis entitled "A Phase III Randomized Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Clinical Trial to Assess the Effects of Feramax When Administered Orally Once a Day on Postoperative Fatigue Levels in Patients Following Elective Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery​" on Friday, September 6th, at 9:00 am.​​​​​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   180
  </id>
  <name>
   Teaching Assistant Professional Development Day 2019
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-09 09:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-09 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/09/teaching_assistant_professional_development_day_2019.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie Student Union Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   Hosted by the Centre for Learning and Teaching, the annual Teaching Assistant Professional Development Day is a free, one-day event is designed for TAs and students who are interested in a teaching career. 
Individuals choose from a variety of concurrent sessions designed to address the essential skills required by undergraduate and graduate students alike to effectively facilitate classes and to enhance their teaching skills.
Come join students from across the Dalhousie campuses!
Visit the CLT webiste for more information: https://www.dal.ca/dept/clt/events-news/annual-events/TA_Days.html​
Register for TA Day 2019: https://surveys.dal.ca/opinio/s?s=49352
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   181
  </id>
  <name>
   Street Naming Ceremony
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-10 10:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-10 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/10/street_naming_ceremony.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Emera IDEA Building, Room 1004
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   alhousie is holding a special ceremony to honour the two new streets on Sexton Campus. The internal streets are to be named Norma Eddy Lane and Da Costa Row, after two important figures in Dalhousie and Canada's histories. The street naming efforts were taken on by our Facilities Management team, with consultation from many groups.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   182
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-11 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-11 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing16.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   183
  </id>
  <name>
   Innovation Rounds: Funding Sources for Health Research and Innovation
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-12 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-12 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/12/innovation_rounds__funding_sources_for_health_research_and_innovation.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Bethune Ballroom, 1st Fl. Bethune Building, VG Site, 1276 South Park St. Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Come learn about health research and innovation funding opportunities available through Innovacorp, ACOA, NRC, MITACS, NSERC, Springboard, NSHA, IWK and more.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   184
  </id>
  <name>
   Registrar's Office Pop-Up Shop
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-13 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-13 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/13/registrar_s_office_pop_up_shop.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Killam Library
  </location>
  <category>
  </category>
  <description>
   The start of a new academic year is an exciting and busy time on campus, and the Registrar's Office is at the heart of the hustle and bustle. Whether we're helping students manage their academic profile, advising faculty members on academic regulations, or supporting staff in navigating the university's processes, the Registrar's Office is a key part of the running of the university and an essential component of what makes Dal a great place to study and work. 

This year, we're excited to be launching a new initiative which will bring our service out on the road and directly to you!
For the first two weeks of term, watch out for our Registrar's Office Pop-up Shops around campus. Posted at locations around our Halifax sites, you'll have the opportunity to meet our friendly RO staff, find out more about our service, and ask us any burning questions you may have.
Students who visit us can also enter our prize draw, which will test your Dal knowledge for a chance to win a fantastic grand prize of an iPad! 

We hope to get the chance to meet as many students, faculty, and staff as possible at our Pop-up Shops around campus, but if you can't get out to see us then, remember that you can visit us at any of our service centre locations, or the Henry Hicks building, to find out what we can do for you.
​We look forward to seeing you soon.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   185
  </id>
  <name>
   Women's Soccer: CBU @ DAL
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-14 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-14 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/14/women_s_soccer__cbu___dal.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Wickwire Field
  </location>
  <category>
   Athletics, Varsity &amp; Club
  </category>
  <description>
   Tigers women's soccer team hosts Cape Breton Capers on Saturday, Sept. 14. Kick off is at 1pm.
Free for DAL students with valid ID!
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free for DAL students with valid ID!
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   186
  </id>
  <name>
   Department of Medical Neuroscience MSc Thesis Defence
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-15 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-15 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/15/department_of_medical_neuroscience_msc_thesis_defence_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   3rd Floor Conference Room, Life Science Research Institute (LSRI)
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   MSc Thesis Defence, Olumide E.S. Adegunna
"The Role of Blood-Brain Barrier Pathology in Post-Traumatic Epilepsy and its Co-Morbidities"
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   187
  </id>
  <name>
   Registrar's Office Pop-Up Shop
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-16 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-16 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/16/registrar_s_office_pop_up_shop.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dal Bookstore
  </location>
  <category>
  </category>
  <description>
   The start of a new academic year is an exciting and busy time on campus, and the Registrar's Office is at the heart of the hustle and bustle. Whether we're helping students manage their academic profile, advising faculty members on academic regulations, or supporting staff in navigating the university's processes, the Registrar's Office is a key part of the running of the university and an essential component of what makes Dal a great place to study and work. 

This year, we're excited to be launching a new initiative which will bring our service out on the road and directly to you!
For the first two weeks of term, watch out for our Registrar's Office Pop-up Shops around campus. Posted at locations around our Halifax sites, you'll have the opportunity to meet our friendly RO staff, find out more about our service, and ask us any burning questions you may have.
Students who visit us can also enter our prize draw, which will test your Dal knowledge for a chance to win a fantastic grand prize of an iPad! 

We hope to get the chance to meet as many students, faculty, and staff as possible at our Pop-up Shops around campus, but if you can't get out to see us then, remember that you can visit us at any of our service centre locations, or the Henry Hicks building, to find out what we can do for you.
​We look forward to seeing you soon.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   188
  </id>
  <name>
   Food System Failure: Why Food is a Forgotten Policy Option
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-17 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-17 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/17/food_system_failure__why_food_is_a_forgotten_policy_option.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The second panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 The right to food is enshrined in international law, while ending hunger is explicit as the second of 17 global sustainable development goals. Yet 4 million Canadians experience food insecurity, diet-related chronic diseases are increasing, and climate change is threatening food supply and production as well as traditional ways of life for many communities across Canada. These complex issues point to a failure of the food system but why isn’t anyone talking about this failure in the run up to the Federal election? 

 In this panel, four speakers will discuss the challenges and opportunities for our 21st century food system, from the perspectives of health, sustainability, economic development, corporate responsibility and law. In doing so, they will address the question, what are the policy levers for a fair, affordable, sustainable and healthy food system for Atlantic Canada?

 Featuring:
 Jamie Baxter (Chair) - Associate Professor in the Schulich School of Law, Dalhousie University
 Megan Bailey - Canada Research Chair in Integrated and Coastal Governance, Dalhousie University
 Sara Kirk - Professor in the School of Health and Human Performance, Scientific Director of the Healthy Populations Institute, Dalhousie University 
 Catherine Mah - Canada Research Chair in Promoting Healthy Populations, Dalhousie University
 Sara Seck - Associate Professor and Associate Dean, Research in the Schulich School of Law, Dalhousie University

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   189
  </id>
  <name>
   NSERC Alliance Grant Program: Outreach Session
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-18 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-18 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/18/nserc_alliance_grant_program__outreach_session.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 303, Student Union Building (SUB)
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   NSERC has recently consolidated its partnership grants (Engage, CRDs, Strategic, Industrial Research Chairs) under the umbrella of the new Alliance Grants Program. You are invited to attend an information session with Gordon Deveau, Deputy Director, NSERC, who will give an update on the program. A question and answer period will follow.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   190
  </id>
  <name>
   David Schroeder Music and Culture Series with Judith Cohen
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-19 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-19 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/19/david_schroeder_music_and_culture_series_with_judith_cohen.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalhousie Arts Centre, 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   DAVID SCHROEDER MUSIC AND CULTURE SERIES
with
JUDITH COHEN
Yiddish and Sephardic Narrative Ballads:   Shared Themes
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   191
  </id>
  <name>
   Dal Biobtliz
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-20 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-20 16:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/20/dal_biobtliz.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Studley Campus - LSC 3rd Floor Reception
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Join us Friday, September 20th to record all the species we can find on Dalhousie's Studley Campus. The Agricultural Campus in Truro will also be bioblitzing with us in tandem.
All are welcome, regardless of your species knowledge. Come by yourself, in pairs, or with a group of your friends! Join one of our naturalist leaders and learn about the biodiversity we share our campus with. You may sign up for one or more of the available time slots and then select the zone or specialty once you register on the day of the event.
Time slots will last approx 1.5 hours and will have leaders to point out target organisms. A few specialized events are below:
7:30-8:30am, Early morning birding event (All Zones)
10:00-11:30am, Bill Freedman Native Plant Collection
12:15-1 pm Urban Nature Walk
8:00-9:00pm, Late night bugging event (Dal main courtyard). A sheet will be set up with lights to attract bugs.
All-Day, Sweep-netting events (Zones 1, 2, 3, and 5 – sign-up for a zone at the registration table)​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   192
  </id>
  <name>
   Dalplex Member Appreciation Week
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-23 06:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-29 22:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/23/dalplex_member_appreciation_week.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalplex
  </location>
  <category>
   Health and Wellness
  </category>
  <description>
   September 23-29 is Member Appreciation Week!


Try our towel service for the week for free!


Enjoy daily complimentary snacks!


Take part in a social media contests for chances to win prizes! 


After your workout, fill out a survey in the lobby and enter for a chance to win a Dalplex Prize pack or one of our grand 
prizes.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   193
  </id>
  <name>
   The Age of Disinformation: Library Supports to Help Students
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-24 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-24 11:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/24/the_age_of_disinformation__library_supports_to_help_students.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Killam Library, Room B400
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   In this session, we will talk about some key information literacy challenges many students face when doing university-level research for the first time, including distinguishing good information from "disinformation." We will also discuss some important subject-specific research resources you can show your students and the other supports that are available for you and your students from the Libraries.
  
Presenter
Lindsay McNiff, MA, MI 
Learning &amp; Instruction Librarian, Dalhousie Libraries 

Lindsay McNiff is the Learning and Instruction Librarian at Dalhousie as well as the liaison librarian to the Centre for Learning and Teaching, the Department of English, and the School of Information Management, where she also teaches graduate courses in the Master of Information Program.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   194
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-25 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-25 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing18.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   195
  </id>
  <name>
   Pink Day Meet and Greet for Facilities Management
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-26 10:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-26 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/26/pink_day_meet_and_greet_for_facilities_management.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   LeMarchant Place Atrium
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   Pink Day celebrates Dal’s commitment to a safe, inclusive, and respectful University community that embraces diversity. 2019 marks 10 years of celebrating Pink Day at Dalhousie!
Meet and Greet with Dal’s new Vice-Provost, Equity &amp; Inclusion 
 Theresa Rajack-Talley. HRES will be on site to facilitate conversation 
 around respect in the workplace and what that means to you.
Coffee/tea and treats will be provided.
Chance to win 1 of 3 coffee/treat breaks for your office/shift team.
dal.ca/PinkDay
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   196
  </id>
  <name>
   4th Annual Suppply Chain &amp; Logistics Management Workshop
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-27 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-27 16:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/27/4th_annual_suppply_chain___logistics_management_workshop.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3089, Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Supply Chains in the 21st Century
Sponsored by the Centre for Research in Sustainable Supply Chain Analytics (CRSSCA) and organized and chaired by Prof. Dr. M. Ali Ülkü, the fourth annual workshop brings in distinguished speakers from diverse industries who are experts in their fields to share their knowledge on the latest trends. It also provides an excellent opportunity to cross-pollinate ideas and network with professionals, academics and students in a highly collegial environment. In our 4th workshop, we will discuss, from varying perspectives for both goods and services, how a sustainable supply chain should operate under the disruption, innovation and advanced technology of the 21st century. Talks will be both academic- and practitioner-oriented.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   197
  </id>
  <name>
   For All The Tea in Zhōngguó: Poetry in Two Languages
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-29 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-29 16:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/29/for_all_the_tea_in_zh_nggu___poetry_in_two_languages.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Canadian Museum of Immigration at Pier 21
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   In celebration of the 10th annual Culture Days, the Museum is pleased to host this unique blend of English and Mandarin poetry readings from the new book For All The Tea in Zhōngguó compiled by Rodger Martin. The result of 30 years of writing, the book has two parts, first, Rodger's poems published in China over the past three decades; second, the work of Chinese New Pastoral poets that he collaborated with over the same period. Rodger will be reading poems in English, and Dr. Shao-Pin Luo, Chinese Studies Professor from Dalhousie University, will be reading poems in Mandarin.
https://pier21.ca/events​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   198
  </id>
  <name>
   10th Annual Dalhousie Mawio'mi
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-09-30 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-09-30 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/30/10th_annual_dalhousie_mawio_mi.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Studley Quad (Rain Location TBD)
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   A day of Mi'kmaw and Indigenous cultural sharing and celebration. We will have the big drum, dancers, and vendors.
Vendor Market starts at 10:30
Feast - 11am- while supplies last
Grand Entry - 12 noon
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   199
  </id>
  <name>
   Canada’s Energy Future: Boom or Bust?
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-01 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-01 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/01/canada_s_energy_future__boom_or_bust_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The fourth panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series.

 This panel asks the question, Can Canada’s energy future address environmental concerns and land disputes, while still generating a successful and profitable energy industry? Or will the needs of various stakeholders leave us in a perpetual state of conflict?

 Three experts on Canada's energy industry will attempt to answer whether we can achieve a balance between competing stakeholders and, if not, what this will mean for Canadians.

 Featuring:

 Larry Hughes (Chair) - Founding Fellow at the MacEachen Institute, Dalhousie University

 Dennis McConaghy - Author and Commentator on Energy and Carbon Policy Issues

 Jacques Poitras - Journalist and Author

 Kristen Zickfield - Associate Professor in the Geography Department, Simon Fraser University

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED. 

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.

 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   200
  </id>
  <name>
   SURGE and OTN Discover Coding
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-02 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-02 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/09/surge_and_otn_discover_coding.event.html/showing3.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   SURGE Sandbox - LSC Oceanography 2660
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   Join SURGE and Ocean Tracking Network (OTN) in our Discover Coding series! During each Wednesday of the fall semester, we will be hosting one hour coding workshops over lunch. The workshops are split into four week topics that build upon each other each week. The workshops will be following the Software Carpentry lessons. The topics we will cover are GitHub, Python and R. It is recommended that you attend all four weeks of a topic to not fall behind. Lunch will be provided for the kick off of the series - Sept 11. Each following week will be a BYOL (Bring Your Own Lunch).
Be sure to come prepared and have the appropriate software(s) downloaded. SURGE will open at noon for students to come and get ready before the workshop officially starts at 12:30.
Schedule:
Sept 11, 18, 25: Intro to GitHub
Oct 2, 9, 16, 23: Intro to Python
Oct 30, Nov 6, 20, 27: Intro to R.
Workshops are free!
Please email surge@dal.ca if you have questions​
Register discovercoding.eventbrite.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   201
  </id>
  <name>
   PhD Candidate Eilidh MacDonald will speak on 'Mechanical Control of Heart Rate'.
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-03 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-03 12:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/03/phd_candidate_eilidh_macdonald_will_speak_on__mechanical_control_of_heart_rate__.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 3H-01, 3rd Floor Tupper Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The 2019-2020 Seminar Series presents current medical research in the fields of physiology and biophysics.
PhD Candidate Eilidh MacDonald will speak on 'Mechanical Control of Heart Rate'.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   202
  </id>
  <name>
   Faculty of Medicine Orientation Forum
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-04 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-04 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/04/faculty_of_medicine_orientation_forum.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Tupper Foyer, Tupper Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Career Services
  </category>
  <description>
   Join us to learn more about the services and resources available to all research trainees in the Faculty of Medicine.
Schedule
11:00 – Welcome
11:05 – Brief Introduction of Presenters
11:45 – Open Forum
12:30 - Pizza for all participants
Presenters include:​​​

Medical Research Development Office (MRDO)
Professional &amp; Research Education Program (PREP)
Faculty of Graduate Studies (FGS)
Dal Connects
Dalhousie Writing Centre
Beatrice Hunter Cancer Research Institute
Student Health &amp; Wellness
Student Access and Academic Support
Histology and Research Services Lab (HRS)
Faculty of Medicine Graduate Students Society (FMGSS) 
Career Services 
Mitacs
International Centre
Dalhousie Medical Research Foundation (DMRF)
Uniweb
Global Health Office (GHO)
CORES
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   203
  </id>
  <name>
   Halifax Drug Use Symposium
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-05 08:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-05 18:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/05/halifax_drug_use_symposium.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   DSU Building- McInnis Room
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   Hosted by Canadians Students for Sensible Drug Policy (CSSDP), the conference will discuss harm reduction as it relates to drug use, and socially just policy alternatives​. Throughout the day we will be hosting various events and opportunities for engagement including a film screening, speakers, and panel discussions. Please join us in the conversation around socially just systemic change to drug policy! Come out for this impassioned day of learning, story telling, and radical compassion.​
For more details and to purchase tickets visit halifaxdrugusesymposium.com​
  </description>
  <cost>
   $35 for regular ticket, $10 for students.
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   204
  </id>
  <name>
   Community Health &amp; Epidemiology Seminar Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-07 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-07 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/07/community_health___epidemiology_seminar_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   CH&amp;E Classroom, Room 409, Centre for Clinical Research, 5790 University Avenue, Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Presenter:  Dr. Neil MacKinnon, Dean, Winkle College of Pharmacy, University of Cincinnati
Title:  Evaluation of Public Policies to Address the Opioid Crisis: What Works?
Abstract:  In this presentation, Dr. MacKinnon will provide an overview of the current state of the opioid crisis in the US, with a focus on Ohio. Sharing examples from his ow n research and from other researchers, he'll provide an update on some of the latest trends of this epidemic. Strategies and policies used by the Ohio Department of Health and others, and the effectiveness of these strategies, will be shared and reviewed. An example of a university and health system (the University of Cincinnati and UC Health) working together to address the opioid crisis through a joint task force will be reviewed as a case study.
Anyone with an interest in the opioid crisis, including those who wonder how we can best address this epidemic, will benefit from this seminar, whether a researcher, clinician, policy maker, health advocate or other.
Learning Objectives:  Describe the magnitude of the opioid crisis nationally and in Ohio; Discuss strategies and policies used in Ohio to address the opioid crisis; Consider how one university and health system in Ohio are addressing the crisis. 
Speaker Bio:  Dr. Neil MacKinnon is Dean and Professor of the James L Winkle College of Pharmacy at the University of Cincinnati. He is also co-chair of the UC/UC Health Opioid Task Force. Prior to his current position, Neil served as Director of the Center for Rural Health at the University of Arizona, which houses the State Office of Rural Health for Arizona. A native of Nova Scotia and a former faculty member at Dalhousie University, Neil co-authored the Canadian bestselling book, Take as Directed, with Rhonda Church, a family physician. Neil has been an adjunct faculty member of the Department of Community Health &amp; Epidemiology since 1999.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   205
  </id>
  <name>
   Human Rights and Reconciliation: Indigenous Child Welfare
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-08 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-08 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/08/human_rights_and_reconciliation__indigenous_child_welfare.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The fifth panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 Events in the last four years have brought significant attention to the issue of Indigenous child welfare. In 2015, the Truth and Reconciliation Commission (TRC) stated that “Canada’s child-welfare system has simply continued the assimilation that the residential school system started,” and its Calls to Action aimed to fix this broken system. In 2016, the Canadian Human Rights Tribunal (CHRT) found that the federal government has been knowingly discriminating against First Nations children by underfunding the First Nations Child and Family Services (FNCFS) Program. Since that time, Canada has been the subject of seven non-compliance orders, including failing to fully implement Jordan’s Principle. 

 In 2018, the Liberals committed to addressing the CHRT’s orders. Finally, in June 2019, Parliament gave royal assent to Bill C-92, to recognize Indigenous People’s jurisdiction over child and family services, as part of an inherent and Aboriginal right to self-governance; to establish national standards in this area, and to contribute to the implementation of the UN Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples (UNDRIP). The bill has received mixed reactions from Indigenous communities.In this panel discussion, three experts in child welfare legislation will discuss these events and what can still be done.

 Featuring:
 Angelina Amaral - Mi’kmaq Governance Manager, Mi’kmaq Rights Initiative
 Cindy Blackstock - Executive Director and Professor in the School of Social Work, McGill University
 Naiomi Metallic - Chancellor’s Chair in Aboriginal Law and Policy, Dalhousie University

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.
 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   206
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-09 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-09 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing19.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   207
  </id>
  <name>
   Federalism and the Politics of Equalization Policy: The Future of Territorial Redistribution in Canada
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-10 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-10 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/10/federalism_and_the_politics_of_equalization_policy__the_future_of_territorial_redistribution_in_canada.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1011, Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax, Nova Scotia
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Daniel Béland, Director of the McGill Institute for the Study of Canada
How should federal money be distributed to Canada's provinces? The federal equalization program attempts to address fiscal disparities between provinces. In part because of its explicitly redistributive nature, equalization is a source of political controversy. The rhetoric of equalization critics such as Alberta Prem​ier Jason Kenney has become increasingly contentious at a time when the federal program features promi nently in debates over issues such as carbon pricing and pipeline building. How can we make sense of these recent developments? What is the future of equalization in Canada and what steps can we take to improve the program, from a political standpoint? The answers to these questions are not straightforward but addressing them now is particularly vital as the 2019 federal election approaches.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   208
  </id>
  <name>
   Understanding Reaction Mechanisms and Structure/Reactivity Relationships in Oxidative Addition to Nickel(0): Implications for Cross-Coupling Catalysis
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-11 13:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-11 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/11/understanding_reaction_mechanisms_and_structure_reactivity_relationships_in_oxidative_addition_to_nickel_0___implications_for_cross_coupling_catalysis.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chemistry Room 226
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Professor David J. Nelson
Department of Chemistry
University of Strathclyde
https://www.strath.ac.uk/staff/nelsondaviddr/
  </description>
  <cost>
   Refreshments will be provided in Chemistry Room 225 at 1:15 pm
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   209
  </id>
  <name>
   Love &amp; Information
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-12 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-12 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/08/love___information.event.html/showing4.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   David Mack. Murray Studio, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Caryl Churchill
Directed by Laura Vingoe-Cram
​The theatrical equivalent of speed-dating, Love and Information is a parade of tiny playlets, each crystallizing a thought about how we love and how we think. In a theatrical experience for the age of Google and Twitter, when even such vast ideas as love are fragmented into soundbites, Caryl Churchill’s dazzling experimental work
finds astonishing depth in each microburst
of drama.
10/08/2019 to 10/12/2019
  </description>
  <cost>
   $15 / $10 for individual tickets or purchase a 5-event package and save!
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   210
  </id>
  <name>
   Resilience or Reluctance: Climate Change Adaptation in Atlantic Canada
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-15 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-15 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/15/resilience_or_reluctance__climate_change_adaptation_in_atlantic_canada.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The sixth panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 The 2019 Canada’s Changing Climate Report (CCCR) projects that Atlantic Canada will experience extreme sea-level change in the coming years. This will result in more frequent high water-level events, causing damage to coastal infrastructure and ecosystem. In many respects, the future is already here. In 2018, for example, floods in New Brunswick affected 12,000 properties and caused $80,000,000 in damages. These events have a drastic impact on both the population’s health and pocketbook. In light of the new CCCR report, this edition of Policy Matters considers questions such as how effective are current policies on resilience and adaptation for the east coast and Canada? What are the tough choices that lie ahead, and how do we address them?

 Featuring:
 Blair Feltmate (Chair) - Professor in the School of Enivronment and Head of the Intact Centre on Climate Adaptation, University of Waterloo
 Omer Chouinard - Emeritus Professor in Environment, Université de Moncton
 Megan Leslie - President and CEO, WWF-Canada
 Kate Sherren - Associate Professor in the School for Resource and Environmental Studies, Dalhousie University
 Robert Strang - Chief Medical Officer of Health, Nova Scotia

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.

 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   211
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-16 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-16 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing20.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   212
  </id>
  <name>
   Workshop Series: Focus on Communication: Informal Speaking
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-17 16:35:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-17 18:25:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/17/workshop_series__focus_on_communication__informal_speaking_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Mona Campbell Building: Room 2110
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   The first of two highly interactive workshops focusing on communication strategies and linguistic resources for a variety of informal contexts, from social situations to shopping to day-to-day life. The workshop will include practice time overseen by an instructor.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   213
  </id>
  <name>
   Si in Ligand Design: Novel Structure and Reactivity Involving Transition Metal silyl Pincer Complexes
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-18 13:15:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-18 13:15:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/18/si_in_ligand_design__novel_structure_and_reactivity_involving_transition_metal_silyl_pincer_complexes_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Chemistry Room 226
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Professor Laura Turculet
Department of Chemistry
Dalhousie University
https://www.dal.ca/faculty/science/chemistry/faculty-staff/our-faculty/laura-turculet.html
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   214
  </id>
  <name>
   Women's Soccer: MtA @ DAL
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-20 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-20 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/20/women_s_soccer__mta___dal.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Wickwire Field
  </location>
  <category>
   Athletics, Varsity &amp; Club
  </category>
  <description>
   Tigers women's soccer team hosts the Mount Allison Mounties​​ on Sunday, Oct 3. Kickoff is at 1pm!
DAL students get in free with valid ID!
  </description>
  <cost>
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   215
  </id>
  <name>
   Meeting the Housing Needs of Older LGBTQ2S+ Canadians
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-22 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-22 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/22/meeting_the_housing_needs_of_older_lgbtq2s__canadians.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The seventh panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 The purpose of this panel discussion is to situate the housing issues facing older LGBTQ2S+ populations in the national policy debate currently underway in light of the recently released Canadian Mortgage and Housing Corporation National Housing Strategy. 

 Given the dearth of data on the needs of older LGBTQ2S+ Canadians, our team is conducting a 1-year Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council (SSHRC) grant to uncover the specific policy and programming gaps and needs of older LGBTQ2S+ Canadians using a 3-phase process: 1. A scoping review of existing housing policies, 2. An online survey of key policy considerations, and 3. In-person consultations in 5 Canadian cities. The key analytic frameworks utilized in this housing study included: 1. Sex and gender-based analysis, 2. PESTEL analysis, and 3. Thematic analysis.

 Featuring:
 Liesl Gambold - Associate Professor in the Department of Sociology and Social Anthropology, Dalhousie University 
 Jacqueline Gahagan - Professor in the School of Health and Human Performance, Dalhousie University
 Shawn Harmon - Policy Analyst and Part-Time Faculty in the
 School of Law, Dalhousie University
 Ren Thomas - Assistant Professor in the School of Planning, Dalhousie University

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.

 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   216
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-23 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-23 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing21.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   217
  </id>
  <name>
   Workshop Series: Focus on Communication: Speaking about Numbers and Statistics
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-24 16:35:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-24 18:25:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/26/workshop_series__focus_on_communication__speaking_about_numbers_and_statistics.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Mona Campbell Building: Room 2110
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   This workshop will cover the grammar of talking about numbers, data, statistics, trends and generalizations.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   218
  </id>
  <name>
   Jillian Keiley Call It Collaboration
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-25 13:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-25 13:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/25/jillian_keiley_call_it_collaboration.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Studio Two Dal Arts Centre 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Jillian Keiley is an award-winning director from St. John's, Newfoundland and founder of Artistic Fraud of Newfoundland. Jillian has directed and taught across Canada and internationally. She was the winner of the Siminovitch Prize for Directing in 2004 and the Canada Council's John Hirsch Prize in 1997. Since 2012 Jillian is the NAC English Theatre Artistic Director. Most recently, she directed The Neverending Story for the Strarford Festival and NAC, and Betwen Breaths for Artistic Fraud, on tour to Neptune Theatre in October 2019
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   219
  </id>
  <name>
   Men's Hockey: UNB @ DAL
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-26 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-26 19:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/26/men_s_hockey__unb___dal.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Halifax Forum
  </location>
  <category>
   Athletics, Varsity &amp; Club
  </category>
  <description>
   Tigers men's hockey team hosts the University of New Brunswick Reds ​on Wednesday, Oct 26. Puck drop is at 7pm!
DAL students get in free with valid ID!
  </description>
  <cost>
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   220
  </id>
  <name>
   Title: Women's Volleyball: ACA @ DAL
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-27 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-27 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/27/_title__women_s_volleyball__aca___dal_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Dalplex
  </location>
  <category>
   Athletics, Varsity &amp; Club
  </category>
  <description>
   Tigers women's volleyball team hosts the Acadia Axewomen on Sunday, Oct 27. Start time is at ​2pm!
DAL students get in free with valid ID! ​
  </description>
  <cost>
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   221
  </id>
  <name>
   When the Dust Settles: How Do We Hold People to Account After Disasters?
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-29 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-29 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/29/when_the_dust_settles__how_do_we_hold_people_to_account_after_disasters_.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The eighth panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 Natural disasters, industrial failures, cyber and terrorist attacks generate intense popular interest and scrutiny. These events raise difficult questions about whether or not enough precautions were put in place to guard against these events. Yet given the complexity of modern systems, it is becoming increasingly difficult to hold people to account for failures: there are just too many people and organizations involved. In a highly interdependent setting, what should accountability look like and how do we achieve it? 

 Featuring:
 Lori Turnbull (Chair) - Director of the School of Public Administration, Dalhousie University
 Bruce Campbell - Adjunct Professor in the Faculty of Environmental Studies, York University
 Paul Kovacs - Founder and Executive Director of the Institute for Catastrophic Loss Reduction
 Jennifer Quaid - Associate Professor, Civil Law Section in the Faculty of Law, University of Ottawa
 Kevin Quigley - Scholarly Director of the MacEachen Institute, Dalhousie University

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.
 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   222
  </id>
  <name>
   Mini Law School: Why "Frankenfoods" Need Feminism
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-30 07:45:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-30 20:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/09/25/mini_law_school__why__frankenfoods__need_feminism.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 104, Schulich School of Law, Weldon Law Building, 6061 University Ave., Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Food production and consumption practices have significant environmental, social, and ethical consequences. As the world population grows, and appetites for animal products increase, new and emerging food innovations like lab-grown meat and genetically engineered animals are increasingly presented as "win-win" solutions to complicated problems like environmental degradation and global hunger. However, there has also been profound resistance to these kinds of developments. A feminist perspective offers a different way of thinking about new food innovations and their relationship with the law, in an effort to better evaluate whether or not they can contribute to the building of a more sustainable and just food system for all.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   223
  </id>
  <name>
   Workshop Series: Focus on Communication: Academic Communication for the Classroom
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-31 16:35:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-10-31 18:25:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/31/workshop_series__focus_on_communication__academic_communication_for_the_classroom.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Mona Campbell Building: Room 2110
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   This workshop will focus on strategies to improve your fluency and communication in academic settings such as tutorial discussions, seminars and labs.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   224
  </id>
  <name>
   The Cuban Revolution at 60 - International Conference
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-10-31 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-02 17:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/31/the_cuban_revolution_at_60___international_conference.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Thursday &amp; Friday – McInnes Room, 2nd floor, Dalhousie Student Union Building, 6136 University Avenue Saturday – Scotiabank Auditorium, ground floor, 6135 University Avenue
  </location>
  <category>
   Conferences
  </category>
  <description>
   Forty internationally renowned Cuba scholars, policy-makers and policy analysts will gather at Dalhousie University in Halifax this fall to take the measure of “The Cuban Revolution at 60.”
All sessions will be open to the public, and free.
The three-day symposium will be highlighted by addresses by two of the key players in the historic 2014 re-opening of relations between Cuba and the United States. Josefina Vidal, now Cuba’s ambassador to Canada and then Cuba’s chief negotiator with the Americans, and Jeffrey DeLaurentis, the first US ambassador to Cuba following the renewal of relations, will each offer personal reflections on what happened then, and what isn’t happening now.
Attendees will also learn the results of the very latest research into a controversial and mysterious ailment reported by some US and Canadian diplomats in Cuba. Dr. Alon Friedman, a ground-breaking neuroscientist at the Dalhousie University Brain Repair Centre who recently led a multidisciplinary study into the so-called “Havana Syndrome” for Global Affairs Canada, will present his findings at the conference.
Leading Cuba specialists from Cuba, the UK, Latin America, Europe, the United States and Canada will also participate in a series of panels to assess the successes and challenges of the Cuban economy, Cuba-US relations and Cuba’s international relations. Other panels will focus on climate change and ecological challenges facing the island, as well as social change, including issues of race, gender (in)equity, health and sexual diversity.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   225
  </id>
  <name>
   Elizabeth Oakes Chamber Music Masterclass
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-04 16:15:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-04 16:15:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/04/elizabeth_oakes_chamber_music_masterclass.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 406 Dal Arts Centre 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   elizabeth-oakes.com
Dal chamber concert: Nov 6, 7:30PM
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   226
  </id>
  <name>
   The Art of the Deal: Public-Private Partnerships
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-05 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-05 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/05/the_art_of_the_deal__public_private_partnerships.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The ninth panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 Public-Private Partnerships (P3s) are controversial. Those in fair underscore the importance of accessing private sector efficiency, expertise and capital. Many remain sceptical. At times, definitions of P3s and the criteria by which to judge them are unclear. This panel will explore P3 in more detail, and consider when and if they generate public value. 

 Featuring:
 Mary Brooks (Chair) - Professor Emerita in the Rowe School of Business, Dalhousie University
 Paul LaFleche - Deputy Minister, Department of Transportation and Infrastructure Renewal, Nova Scotia
 Ray Mitchell - Legal Counsel
 Matti Siemiatycki - Interim Director, School of Cities, University of Toronto

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.
 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   227
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-06 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-06 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing23.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   228
  </id>
  <name>
   David Schroeder Music &amp; Culture Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-07 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-07 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/07/david_schroeder_music___culture_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 406 in the Dahousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Margot Fassler
Keough-Hesburgh Professor of Music History and Liturgy (University of Notre Dame) and Professor of Music History, Emerita (Yale University)
HILDEGARD OF BINGEN AND HER SCRIBES
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   229
  </id>
  <name>
   Laura Sgroi Composition Masterclass
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-08 09:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-08 09:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/08/laura_sgroi_composition_masterclass.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 121 Dal Arts Centre 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   laurasgroimusic.com
Laura's composition "We're Not Done Drumming" performed by SNS: Nov 7, 7:30 pm
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   230
  </id>
  <name>
   Symphony Nova Scotia Reading Sessions of Composition Students' Works Conducted by Daniel Bartholomew-Poyser
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-13 10:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-13 10:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/13/symphony_nova_scotia_reading_sessions_of_composition_students__works_conducted_by_daniel_bartholomew_poyser.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 121 Dal Arts Centre 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   symphonynovascotia.ca
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   231
  </id>
  <name>
   Mini Medical School 2019 Program
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-14 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-14 21:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/14/mini_medical_school_2019_program.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   5850 College Street, Theatre B - Tupper Link Building.
  </location>
  <category>
   Community Interest
  </category>
  <description>
   Dr. Nancy Murphy – Drugs We are Seeing on the Street – 7-815pm 
and 
Dr. Thomas Ransom – Foods or Comestibles 8:15 – 9:30pm
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
   5
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   232
  </id>
  <name>
   A Cross-Canada Tour with the Leap &amp; Friends: A Green New Deal for All
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-17 19:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-17 21:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/17/a_cross_canada_tour_with_the_leap___friends__a_green_new_deal_for_all.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   St. Andrew's United Church 6036 Coburg Road Halifax, NS B3H 1Y9
  </location>
  <category>
   Special Events
  </category>
  <description>
   This June, The Leap is hitting the road to build a wave of popular support behind the Green New Deal in Canada. This seven-city tour will include stops in Halifax, Toronto, Montreal, Ottawa, Vancouver, Winnipeg, and Edmonton. Each evening will feature amazing speakers, art and music, and close with a "barnstorm" led by 350.org. 
Speakers and performers include:
David Suzuki
Ingrid Waldron
Tina Oh
El Jones
The Leap's Katie McKenna
We will hear from community leaders, artists, and activists about::
1) How the climate crisis is affecting our communities;
2) Who's responsible for the mess we're in; and
3) How the Green New Deal can build a better economy and society – and how we can make it happen.
 The evening will close with a 'barnstorm' led by 350.org.
Organizing Partner: 350.org
Local Partner: The ENRICH Project
Media Sponsor: Briarpatch Magazine
National Partners: Climate Strike Canada, Canadian Union of Postal Workers, The Council of Canadians, Courage, Delivering Community Power, Migrant Workers Alliance for Change
 
This is a child-friendly event, but no childminding will be available.
If cost is a barrier to you attending this event, contact batul@theleap.org
Accessibility Info:
·        Gender-neutral bathrooms
·        Wheelchair accessible building​
  </description>
  <cost>
   $10
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   233
  </id>
  <name>
   Chamber Music on Both Sides of the Bridge
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-18 19:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-18 19:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/18/chamber_music_on_both_sides_of_the_bridge.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   First Baptist Church, 1300 Oxford St. Halifax
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   The Fountain School's brightest and best travel off campus for two evenings of exquisite chamber music. In the fall, an all-instrumental concert in Halifax, with voice students joining in for the spring program in Cole Harbour. Admission for both events is by donation at the door.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   234
  </id>
  <name>
   Not All Fun and Games: Tough Choices in Cultural Infrastructure Investments
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-19 12:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-19 13:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/19/not_all_fun_and_games__tough_choices_in_cultural_infrastructure_investments.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 1020, Kenneth C. Rowe Management Building, 6100 University Avenue, Halifax,
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The tenth panel in the MacEachen Institute's ten-week Policy Matters Speaker Series. 

 The decision to invest in Cultural and Recreational Infrastructure (CRI)—community centres, museums, music halls, swimming pools and ice rinks, for example—can help further important social, cultural, environmental, economic and health goals for the province.While the aspirations for these investments may be laudable and ambitious, there are limits to funding and capacity. As different orders of government are set to allocate funds for CRI in the coming years, decision makers must make difficult decisions that reconcile important but sometimes competing priorities, such social and environmental concerns, on the one hand, and financial and economic on the other. This panel will report on new research that examines the policy context for CRI decision-making in Nova Scotia and governance frameworks that can assist with difficult decisions and make values and trade-offs more explicit.

 Featuring:
 Darrell Dexter (Chair) - Vice Chair, Global Public Affairs
 Bill Greenlaw - Executive Director, Communities, Culture and
 Heritage, Nova Scotia
 Kevin Quigley - Scholarly Director of the MacEachen Institute,
 Dalhousie University

 THIS EVENT IS FREE AND OPEN TO THE PUBLIC. REGISTRATION IS NOT REQUIRED. SEATING IS FIRST COME, FIRST SERVED.

 This event will be live streamed on Facebook Live at Facebook.com/DALMIPP.
 More information at Dal.ca/mipp​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   235
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-20 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-20 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing25.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   236
  </id>
  <name>
   Andrea Ludwig Masterclass for Singers
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-21 11:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-21 11:30:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/21/andrea_ludwig_masterclass_for_singers.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Room 121 Dal Arts Centre 6101 University Ave
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   andrealudwig.ca
SNS performance: Nov 21, 7:30 pm
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   237
  </id>
  <name>
   Health Law &amp; Policy Seminar Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-22 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-22 13:45:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/22/health_law___policy_seminar_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Weldon Law Building Room 104
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   The Impact of the Child Welfare System on Maternal Health
Meaghan Thuman, Department of Social Policy and Intervention, University of Oxford, United Kingdom
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   238
  </id>
  <name>
   Board of Governors Meeting
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-26 15:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-26 18:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/10/15/board_of_governors_meeting.event.html/showing1.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   University Hall, Macdonald Building
  </location>
  <category>
   Meetings
  </category>
  <description>
   The Board of Governors meeting schedule, meeting agenda, and guidelines for guests are available on the Board of Governors​​ page.
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   239
  </id>
  <name>
   SharePoint Office Hours
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-27 11:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-27 12:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/05/08/sharepoint_office_hours.event.html/showing26.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Online via Microsoft Teams
  </location>
  <category>
   Training &amp; Professional Development
  </category>
  <description>
   SharePoint Office Hours are support sessions for Dalhousie employees with questions about their SharePoint site. Sessions are held online every Wednesday from 11 am to 12 noon via Microsoft Teams, so you can connect with a SharePoint expert without leaving your office.
For more details or to register, visit the SharePoint Information myDal site (login required):
https://dalu.sharepoint.com/sites/admin/spinfo​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   240
  </id>
  <name>
   Workshop Series: Focus on Communication: English Pronunciation
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-28 16:35:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-28 18:25:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/28/workshop_series__focus_on_communication__english_pronunciation.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Mona Campbell Building: Room 2110
  </location>
  <category>
   Workshops
  </category>
  <description>
   This workshop will focus on the mechanics, sounds and rhythm of English to improve your pronunciation issues. The workshop includes theory as well as practice time.​
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   241
  </id>
  <name>
   Health Law &amp; Policy Seminar Series
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-29 12:30:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-29 13:45:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/29/health_law___policy_seminar_series.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Weldon Law Building Room 104
  </location>
  <category>
   Lectures, Seminars
  </category>
  <description>
   Institutional Violence and Disability Memorials
Linda Steele, Faculty of Law, Humanities and the Arts, University of Wollongong, Australia
  </description>
  <cost>
   Free
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
 <event>
  <id>
   242
  </id>
  <name>
   The Women of Troy
  </name>
  <start_date_time>
   2019-11-30 14:00:00
  </start_date_time>
  <end_date_time>
   2019-11-30 14:00:00
  </end_date_time>
  <web_link>
   https://www.dal.ca/news/events/2019/11/26/the_women_of_troy.event.html/showing4.html
  </web_link>
  <location>
   Sir James Dunn Theatre, Dalhousie Arts Centre
  </location>
  <category>
   Concerts, Performances &amp; Arts
  </category>
  <description>
   Euripides
Translated by Don Taylor
Directed by Samantha WilsA city has been shattered by desire. Triumphant after the final battle of the Trojan War, Menelaus comes to take back his wife, Helen, whom he blames for starting the conflict by attracting the Trojan prince Paris. Now, all the women of Troy must face the wrath of the conquering soldiers and must fight for their lives and for their freedom. Written in 415 BC, Euripides’ wrenching exploration of violence and broken love amid the horrors of war is a play distressingly never out of date. on
  </description>
  <cost>
   $15 / $10 for individual tickets or puchase a 5-event package and save!
  </cost>
  <building_id>
  </building_id>
 </event>
</list>